到洛杉磯來吧!
Come to Los Angeles.
這兒陽光普照
The sun shines bright.
海灘寬廣迷人
The beaches are wide and inviting.
橘子園一望無際
And the orange groves stretch as far as the eye can see.
就業機會多多
There are jobs aplenty.
洛 城 機 密
土地價格低
Land is cheap.
每個人都可以擁有自己的房子
Every workingman can have his own house.
每棟房子都住著快樂的一家人
And inside every house, a happy all-American family.
你可以享有這一切
You can have all this.
更棒是
And who knows?
或許你會被星探挖掘
You could even be discovered
一舉成為大明星
become a movie star,
或碰上大明星
or at least see one.
洛杉磯一切都很好
Life is good in Los Angeles.
有如人間天堂一般
It's paradise on earth.
以上說法純屬推銷廣告
That's what they tell you, anyway.
透過影視媒體
Because they're selling an image.
加強這種好印象
They're selling it through movies, radio and television.
就像是熱門連續劇《警網群英》
In the hit show, Badge of Honor,
洛城警探個個神勇非凡
the L.A. cops walk on water
所有歹徒聞風喪膽
as they keep the city clean of crooks.
沒錯  你會覺得這兒簡直是伊甸園一般
You'd think this place was the Garden of Eden.
但即使是天堂  也會有敗類
But there's trouble in paradise
有個敗類叫麥爾哈里斯·柯漢
and his name is Meyer Harris Cohen,
愛戴他的人則稱呼他 米奇C
Mickey C, to his fans.
一個使洛城蒙羞的人物
Local L.A. color to the nth degree.
以及他的頭號保鏢
And his number one bodyguard
錢寧史當·巴那多
Johnny Stompanato.
米奇是洛城黑社會的總把子
Mickey C's the head of organized crime in these parts.
旗下行業淫毒偷搶騙一應俱全
He runs dope, rackets and prostitution.
一年總得幹掉十來個人
He kills a dozen people a year.
而且手法永遠不落俗套
And the dapper little gent does it in style.
每次他的照片一上頭版
And every time his picture's on the front page
就使得洛城的形象大為受損
it's a black eye for the image of Los Angeles.
這種知法犯法的黑道血拼
Because how can organized crime exist
怎能發生在警力雄厚的洛城?
in the city with the best police force in the world?
該是有人出手的時候了
Something has to be done.
只不過手法無啥新意
But nothing too original
誰叫這裏是專炒冷飯的好萊塢
because, hey, this is Hollywood.
米奇·柯漢的下場就像其它教父
What worked for Al Capone would work for the Mickster.
柯漢先生你被捕了
Mr. Cohen, you're under arrest.
罪名是"逃漏綜合所得稅"
Nonpayment of federal income tax.
可是情況並未好轉
But all is not well.
把米奇送進牢裏  使得總把子的位子空出來了
Sending Mickey up has created a vacuum.
早晚總會有個不怕死的想接手所有地盤
And it's only a matter of time
想要取而代之
before someone with balls of brass tries to fill it.
敬告各位親愛的讀者
"Remember, dear readers
第一手的獨家秘聞  絕對機密!
you heard it here first
只有收錄在這本噓噓雜誌
off the record on the q.t and very Hush-Hush."
米奇黑牢秘聞  好萊塢女同性戀
警員 巴德·懷特
你跟聖誕老公公一樣全照著那張名單
You're like Santa Claus with that list.
只不過在你名單上的全是些爛人!
Except everyone on it's been naughty.
他才剛出獄半個月
Guy's been out of Q two weeks.
以後再處理吧
Leave it for later.
我們還得去替大伙買酒呢
We've got to pick up the booze and get it to the station.
好萊塢分局  這裏是6A7車
Hollywood, this is 6-Adam-7.
請總局派車到常春路4216號
Have Central send a prowler to 4216 Evergreen.
有假釋犯因家庭糾紛出手傷人
Parole violation: assault arising from a family dispute.
我們不會留在現場
We won't be here. They'll see him.
別哭了
Quit whining!
別一天到晚哭哭啼啼的
Quit whining all the time! It makes me sick!
搞得我煩死了  閉嘴!
Shut up!
你是誰啊?
Who the hell are you?
聖誕夜的昔日鬼魂
The ghost of Christmas past.
換個男的跟你玩玩吧!
Dance with a man for a change?
你是哪兒來的癟三?
What are you, a smart ass?
你關個一年半就可以出來了
You could be out in a year or half
我會請人在牢裏好好照顧你
I'll get cozy with your parole officer.
只要你敢再碰她
You touch her again,
我會告你強姦未成年少女
I'll have you violated on a kiddies rapper beef.
想知道牢裏怎麼照顧這種人?
You know what they do to kiddies rappers in Quentin.
你有地方可以去嗎?
You have someplace you can go?
去找個地方安頓下來
Go get yourself fixed up.
聖誕快樂
Merry Christmas.
聖誕快樂  夫人
Merry Christmas, ma'am.
走吧!
Let's go,Bud.
大夥一定在等我們了
The guys will be waiting.
傑克·文生 警官
你在警網群英扮演什麼角色?
What do you do on Badge of Honor?
我是技術顧問
I'm the technical advisor.
我教男主角怎麼演才會像警察
I teach Brett Chase how to walk and talk like a cop.
可是他演得並不像你
Brett Chase doesn't walk and talk like you.
他演的是電視精華版
That's because he's the television version.
美國人暫時還受不了真實版
America isn't ready for the real me.
你真是逮捕勞勃米契的人?
Is it true you're the one who arrested Bob Mitchum?
那些演員很喜歡演員警
Badge of Honor guys pretend.
當真的警察一定很刺激吧!
But being the real thing must be a thrill.
我們何不找個安靜的地方
Why don't we go someplace quiet?
聽聽我如何破案的故事
I'll give you the lowdown on Mitchum.
大文 傑克·文生
Big V.Jack Vincennes.
可以讓給我嗎?  當然可以
-May I have this dance? -Of course.
凱倫  這位是噓噓雜誌的席德哈金斯
This is Sid Hudgens with Hush-Hush magazine.
你好! 凱倫
Hello, Karen.
好你個頭
Hello yourself.
怎麼回事啊?
What's that about?
我們有篇好萊塢女同性戀的報導
We did a piece, "Ingenue Dikes in Hollywood."
提到了她的名字
Her name got mentioned.
喂  傑克
Jackie-boy
我有個朋友賣了些大麻給麥特·雷諾
a friend just sold some reefer to Matt Reynolds.
他目前在泰米喬登家裏
He's tripping the light fantastic with Tammy Jordan.
對不起!我剛剛沒注意聽
Sorry, I lost you for a second, Sid.
大都會影業旗下的兩位演員
Contract players, Metro.
你逮捕他們  我下一期雜誌就好好捧捧你
You pinch them, I do a nice feature next issue.
照樣外加五十元現金
Plus the usual $50 cash.
不行  這次得多加五十才行
No, I need another $50.
兩名警察各二十元
Two $20's for two patrolmen,
剩下十元給好萊塢分局的值日警官
a dime for the Hollywood Station watch commander.
傑克  聖誕夜嘛
Jackie, it's Christmas.
不  不是  是非法持有大麻
No, it's not. It's felony possession of marijuana.
事實上是發行量突破三萬六  而且一路往上竄升
Actually, it's circulation 36,000 and climbing.
沒有人知道會紅到什麼地步
There's no telling where this will go.
電台、電視都有可能
Radio, television.
只要把大眾求知的胃口養大了
Once you whet the public's appetite for the truth,
自然鴻運當頭  擋都擋不住
the sky's the limit.
艾德·艾斯利 警官
艾德·艾斯利警官
Sergeant Ed Exley,
傳奇英雄普瑞斯頓·艾斯利之子
son of the legendary Preston Exley.
你一定覺得很難趕得上他吧?
Must be a hard act to follow.
你為什麼不另去闖一片天地?
Why not make a mark somewhere else?
為什麼還要當警察呢?
Why become a cop, Ed?
我喜歡幫助人
I like to help people.
聽說今晚有兩名警察遭到攻擊
We heard 2 officers were assaulted this evening.
你對此有什麼看法?
-What do you think about that?
幹這一行本來就有危險的
-Goes with the job.
不過我看過報告了
I took the report.
他們沒事了
Luckily, they're okay.
你現在就當值勤官不會太年輕嗎?
Aren't you young to be watch commander?
只有今晚而已
It's only tonight.
局裏已婚的都放團圓假了
The married men have Christmas Eve off.
這句話很適合做我的開場白
That's a good lead for the story.
聖誕快樂!長官
Merry Christmas, Captain.
史密斯組長別那麼一板一眼的  保比
-Captain Smith. -Drop the formalities, Bobby.
聖誕節嘛!
-It's Christmas
叫我杜德利就好了
Eve, call me Dudley.
我已經為報導擬好標題了
-I came up with a title for the story.
我想用"與洛城警局共渡平安夜 "
I'm calling it "Silent Night with the LAPD."
非常好嘛!
That's grand.
別忘了!
Now remember, Bobby, that's "Smith."
我姓史密斯  一個S
With an "S."
謝謝你們!  謝謝!
Thank you, gentlemen.
聖誕快樂!  謝謝!
Merry Christmas.
悠著點  小伙子
Hold on there, lads.
聖誕快樂
Merry Christmas.
我看過考試的結果了
I saw the test results on the lieutenant's exam.
你在23人中名列榜首
First out of 23.
你打算調到哪兒?
What'll it be, then?
巡邏  政風  還是哪兒?
Patrol Division? Internal Affairs? What?
我想到刑事局來
I was thinking Detective Bureau.
埃德蒙  你是權謀型的人物
Edmund you're a political animal.
你能洞悉人性的弱點
You have the eye for human weakness,
卻沒有硬漢的膽識
but not the stomach.
你錯了  長官
You're wrong, sir.
對一個你明知有罪的人  你願意用栽贓的方式
Would you be willing to plant evidence on a suspect you knew to be guilty
以確保法院判他有罪嗎?
in order to insure an indictment?
這些我們以前談過了
-We've been over this.
願不願意?
-Yes or no?
不願意
No.
你願意用嚴刑拷打的方式讓犯人招供嗎?
Would you beat a confession out of a suspect you knew to be guilty?
不願意
No.
你會從背後射殺一個頑劣的罪犯
Would you shoot a hardened criminal in the back
以免律師為他脫罪?
in order to offset the chance that some lawyer--
不會
No.
那看在上帝的份上  別干刑警
Then for the love of God don't be a detective.
去你不用做出這種事的地方
Work where you don't have to make those kind of choices.
杜德利  我知道你是一片好意
Dudley, I know you mean well
可是我不見得要學你或者是我父親
but I don't need to do it the way you did or my father.
那至少把你的眼鏡拿掉吧
At least get rid of the glasses.
我想不出來局裏有誰戴眼鏡的
I can't think of a man on the Bureau who wears them.
哪天我被搶了 你們最好快點來
If I get held up, you guys better be here.
嗨  尼克
Hi, Nick.
替我送些酒到家裏去
I need a delivery.
琴酒、蘭姆、威士忌各一箱
A case each of gin, rum, Scotch.
聽來好像是很盛大的派對
Sounds like a hell of a party.
馬上就好
Be right with you.
聖誕快樂
Merry Christmas.
祝你聖誕快樂  警察先生
Merry Christmas to you, officer.
一眼就看出來啦
That obvious?
就寫在你的額頭上
It's practically stamped on your forehead.
你的酒
There you go.
去看看他有什麼事  巴茲
See what he wants, Buzz.
喂  閃一邊去好不好?
Get lost, why don't you?
趴下  頭低下去
Down! Get your fucking head down.
我有執照的
I got a license for that.
少來了  我以前也是警察
Cut me some slack. I used to be a cop.
李蘭·米克斯  沒聽說過
" Leland Meeks." Never heard of you.
大伙都叫我巴茲
They call me Buzz.
我才不管大伙叫你什麼
I don't give a rat's ass what they call you.
頭低下去
Keep your head down.
別亂動  巴茲
And stay thereBuzz.
你沒事吧?
You okay?
她很好
She's fine.
我不是在問你
I'm not asking you, sir.
有人打你嗎?
Somebody hit you?
事情不是你想的那樣
It's not what you think.
那事情是怎樣的?
What is it, then?
你誤會了  先生  我很好的
You got the wrong idea, mister. I'm fine.
但是謝謝你的關心
But it's nice to know you care.
小心開車
Drive safely.
怎麼回事?
What's going on?
你認識他嗎?
You know him?
見過幾次
Yeah, I've seen him around.
他以前是警察
He used to be a cop.
屋內沒開燈  他們在聖誕樹下鬧翻天了
They're sitting in the dark, goofing on the Christmas tree.
相機擺這兒
Put your camera right there.
我出來以後  會走到這兒來
When I walk out, I'll stop here.
你就用首映會場做背景照一張
Get the movie premiere in the background.
我喜歡
I like it.
首映會場上巨星吸大麻被捕
"The Movie Premiere Pot Bust."
我走出來的時候可別用閃光燈照我
When I walk out, I don't want your floodlights in my eyes.
沒問題!  聽到了沒有?
Consider it done. You hear that, Chip?
好了  走吧
Come on.
低一點  開燈
Go! Pop them!
不許動  我是警察
Freeze! Police!
快點快走
Come on. Come on, let's go.
我老婆孩子明天就要來了
My family's coming in--
好好當個聖誕禮物吧
-It'll be a nice Christmas gift.
你好  泰米
-Hi, Tammy.
你好  麥特
-Hi, Matt.
看這邊  轉過來
Right over here.
等一下  行了
-Just turn. -Hold it. Got it!
"首映場上巨星吸大麻被捕 "
-The Movie Premiere Pot Bust!
把他們帶到好萊塢分局去
-Take them in.
我去搜集證據
I'll get the evidence.
法蘭西皇朝
天使之城的平安夜
"It's Christmas Eve in the City of Angels
善良的市民都已酣然入睡
and while decent citizens sleep the sleep of the righteous
癮君子卻汲汲然找尋著大麻
hopheads prowl for marijuana
全然不知有人要來阻止他們
not knowing that a man is coming to stop them:
那人就是著名的犯罪終結者傑克·文生
Celebrity crime-stopper, Jack Vincennes.
所有癮君子的剋星
Scourge of grasshoppers and dope fiends everywhere."
喜歡嗎?  傑克老弟
You like it?
喜歡  文筆很好
Yeah, subtle.
怎麼去那麼久?
What took you?
我的夥伴中途跑去幫小姐了
My partner stopped to help a damsel in distress.
他根本搞不清楚輕重緩急
His priorities are all screwed up.
又玩老把戲了  巴德
Up to your old tricks again, Bud?
傑克  好萊塢傑克
Hollywood Jack,
是什麼風把你吹到我們這個窮鄉僻壤來的
what brings you to our humble station house?
你們好嗎?  你來做什麼?
-How are you? -Why are you here?
我在維持市區的治安啊
You know me. Keeping the streets safe.
讓她們穿上衣服  然後收押
Take these two, get them dressed and book them.
大伙都在樓上
-The party's upstairs.
我馬上上去
-Okay, I'll be right up.
這幹什麼?
What's that for?
你是今晚的值勤官  對吧?
You are watch commander tonight, aren't you?
那有怎樣?
Yeah. So?
這是噓噓雜誌的一點心意
A gratuity from Hush-Hush magazine.
拿去買雙新鞋也好
Buy yourself some new loafers.
不用了  謝謝  你自己留著吧
No thanks, Jack. You keep your payoff.
我沒興趣
I'm not interested.
什麼事?
What the hell is this?
他們就是攻擊布朗跟黑倫的那六個墨西哥人
Six spics. Mexicans, sir. The ones who assaulted Brown and Helenowski.
聽說黑倫大量失血而布朗昏迷不醒
I heard Helenowski bled 6 pints and Brown's in a coma.
他們只受了點輕傷回家去了
They have bruises and muscle pulls.
我聽說的可不是這樣
It's not what I heard.
把他們帶進牢房去
Get them into lock up.
喂  史丹斯
Stens,
有沒有聽說那六個墨西哥人怎麼整布朗他們的?
you guys hear what those taco benders did to Helenowski and Brown?
黑倫失去了一隻眼睛
Helenowski lost an eye,
而布朗則已經奄奄一息了
and they're reading Brown his last rites.
他們今年的聖誕節過得可真是凄慘呀
That ought to make for a very merry Christmas for them.
喂  各位
Hey, guys.
各位  他們抓到墨西哥人了
Guys. They brought the Mexicans in.
人就在樓下
They're downstairs.
史丹斯  過去出口氣
-Let's do it.
對  大夥兒快點去出口氣
-Come on, guys. Let's get them.
喂  史丹斯  派對是在樓土
Stensland, the party's upstairs.
這兒沒你們的事
This doesn't concern you.
拜託  你們都沒事幹嗎?
Come on, guys. Haven't you got work?
回派對上去
Go back to the party.
這是聖誕節呀  幫幫忙好嗎?
-Come on, it's Christmas, help me out.
走開
-Move it!
我只剩下幾個問題而已
I just got a few more questions.
你們用不著進來的
You don't have to be here.
上
Go!
你最好拉住你的夥伴  免得他殺人
You better put a leash on your partner before he kills somebody.
給他一點教訓
Teach him a lesson!
史丹斯  揍他
Get him, Stens!
這是為我們兄弟出氣的  土蛋
This is for ours, Poncho.
揍他  史丹斯
Get him, Stens!
讓我過去
Let me through!
他又沒做什麼事
No! He didn't do nothing!
你看什麼看
What are you looking at?
叫那個墨西哥人閉嘴
Tell that Mexican to shut up!
你有病啊
You're sick!
你別攪局啊  退後
Don't break it up. Get back! Get back!
去你媽的
Yeah, and fuck your mother!
去你的
Fuck you!
住手!這是命令
Stop, officer! That's an order!
我會把你們全記上去的
You'll all be in my report!
"血腥的聖誕節 "
"Bloody Christmas."
媒體最喜歡亂下標題
The press love to label.
你應該知道此事非同小可
You should know this is bigger than the police board.
大陪審團已經成立了
The grand jury's convening.
搞不好真的會起訴
Indictments may be handed down.
你會出庭作證嗎?
Will you testify?
不會的  長官  我不會
No, sir. I won't.
你要不要跟羅檢察官談一談
District Attorney Loew?
你跟史丹斯送酒到了局裏
You and officer Stensland brought the liquor to the station.
史丹斯當時已經醉了
Stensland was already drunk.
你如果自動出面指控他
Appearing as a voluntary witness against him
將可以減輕對你自己的傷害
could offset damage to yourself.
我不會出面指證自己的夥伴
I won't testify against him,
或是任何人的
or anyone else.
他真是警界之恥呀
This man is a disgrace.
你的槍跟警徽交出來
Your badge and gun, officer.
你被停職了
You're suspended from duty.
解散
Dismissed.
我們需要警員擔任證人  來化解對本局的傷害
We need police witnesses to offset the damage done to the Department.
正義必須伸張
Justice has to be served.
我當然願意作證
Of course I'll testify.
我很高興你有這樣的想法
I'm glad you feel that way, Edmund.
大多數人都不會
Most don't.
他們以為沉默跟正直是同一碼子事
They think silence and integrity are the same thing.
他們跟我們建立的警員形象實在差太遠了
Not exactly the image of the new LAPD we're trying to create.
歡迎光臨未來之城洛杉磯
Welcome to Los Angeles, the city of the future.
我可以提出建議嗎  長官?
-May I make a suggestion, sir?
你儘管說
-By all means.
民眾一定以為我們會大事化小
The public will expect the Department to sweep this under the carpet.
不會
Don't.
拿退休金已萬無一失的人開刀
Shift the guilt to men whose pensions are secured.
強迫他們退休
Force them to retire.
可是還是得重罰一些人
But somebody has to swing.
所以要徹底查辦理查德·史丹斯跟巴德·懷特
So indict, try and convict Richard Stensland and Bud White.
而且一定要讓他們坐牢
Secure them jail time.
這樣話就說得很明瞭
The message will be clear.
本局絕對無法忍受
This Department
自以為凌駕在法律之上的警員
will not tolerate officers who think they're above the law.
史丹斯本來就是警界之恥
Dick Stensland is an embarrassment as a policeman.
他的歷任長官都說他貪贓枉法
He's had rotten fitness reports from every C.O. he's served under.
可是巴德·懷特是個難得的人才
But Bud White is a valuable officer.
懷特根本沒長腦子
White's a mindless thug.
不  埃德蒙
No, Edmund
我問你的那些問題  他都可以回答"願意"
but he can answer "yes" to those questions I've asked you before.
警局跟民眾都需要模範警察
The Department and the public need role models.
儀表出眾為人正直  可以讓民眾崇拜的人
Clean-cut, forthright men the public can admire.
巡佐  我晉陞你為隊長
Sergeant I'll promote you to lieutenant
立即生效
effective immediately.
刑事隊長
Detective Lieutenant.
艾德  你才三十歲
Ed, you're 30.
你父親三十三才升隊長的
Your father didn't make lieutenant till he was 33.
我知道  長官
I know that, sir.
而他升隊長時正是升為刑事隊長
When he made lieutenant, it was as a detective.
在我們開慶功宴前
Before we start polishing our laurels
最好先找個預備證人
it'd look better if we had a corroborative witness.
這可不太好找了
That won't be easy to come by.
大伙最恨這種打小報告的人
The men hate a stool pigeon.
傑克·文生
Jack Vincennes.
他出手打了其中一個
He hit one of the Mexicans.
像文生這種老賊叫他承認自己的過失還有可能
A veteran like Vincennes might be willing to admit his own culpability
要他出賣同僚根本不可能
but he'd never rat out a fellow officer.
傑克是警網群英的技術顧問
Jack's the technical advisor on Badge of Honor.
他靠那個吃飯的
He lives for it.
我們就從這方面著手
That's how to get to him.
我希望你能在一旁觀察
I'd like you to observe, Ed.
叫文生警官進來
Call Sergeant Vincennes.
很聰明的孩子
Bright kid.
你或許可以蒙受其利
You may reap the benefit
可是你受得了局裏同仁鄙視的眼神嗎?
but are you ready to be despised in the Department?
是的  長官  我受得了
Yes, sir, I am.
那就這樣吧
So be it.
隊長  我們就開門見山
Sergeant, we'll get right to it.
有九位市民指證你毆打加西亞
Nine civilian witnesses have identified you as hitting Ezekiel Garcia.
不過我們有位證人願意指認所有涉案的人
But we have a witness who will name names
並且證明你是在被打了以後才出手還擊的
and testify that you hit back
還有呢?
only after being hit.
而你將指證  只有三名已拿到退休金的人涉案
You will testify against 3 officers
其它人則屬無辜
who have earned their pensions and plead ignorance about the rest.
不必  謝了  我不是那種打小報告的人
No thanks. I'm not a snitch.
我保證只對你從輕處以停職的處份
I'll guarantee you a slap on the wrist, a brief suspension
然後把你暫時由緝毒組調到風化組去
followed by a temporary transfer from Narcotics to Vice.
等你由風化組調回來  一樣可以回去做節目
You transfer out of Vice, you'll be back on the show.
節目?
The show?
警網群英啊  文生
Badge of Honor, Vincennes.
我們得暫時減少你的曝光率
We need to tone down your profile for a bit.
我看你一直都很聰明的
I doubt you've ever taken a stupid breath.
可別突然變笨了
Don't start now.
好  我作證就是了
Okay, I'll do it.
大陪審團明天會聽取你的證詞  你可以離開了
The grand jury will hear your testimony tomorrow.
那就這樣好了  警官
And so it goes Detective Lieutenant.
明天在大陪審團前好好表現一下
Ace them at the grand jury tomorrow, son.
穿套帥一點的西裝好好秀一下
Wear a smart-looking suit and ace them.
還有艾德  把眼鏡拿掉
And Ed lose the glasses.
原來你就是那一個證人
So you're the stellar witness.
我應該猜到的
I should have known.
局長給了你什麼?
What's the Chief throwing you?
給了我什麼?
Throwing me?
對呀!給了你什麼好處
Yeah, Exley, what's the payoff?
你是給好處的專家
You're the payoff expert.
而我只是盡我的職責而已
I'm just doing my duty.
好了  你只不過是  抓到一個大好良機而已  大學生
Come on, you're playing an angle here, college boy.
你一定是得了什麼好處
You'll get something so you don't have to hobnob with the cops
所以以後用不著跟那些  恨你入骨的同仁打交道了
who'll hate you for snitching.
如果他們升你的話  你得小心點了
If they're making you detective, watch out.
局裏有些人這一次會死的很慘
Some Bureau guys will burn in this
而你將會跟他們的朋友一起工作
and you'll be working with their friends.
那你自己呢?
What about you?
我只不過糾出三個老掉牙的傢伙
I'm snitching 3 old-timers
他們下個禮拜就會在奧勒岡釣魚了
who'll be fishing in Oregon next week.
跟你比起來我可是清清白白
Next to you, I'm clean
真聰明
and smart.
埃德蒙艾斯利請人庭
Edmund J. Exley to chambers.
還有  別忘了
And remember
如果你的證詞毀了巴德·懷特的一生 他會整死你的
Bud White will fuck you for this if it takes the rest of his life.
組長  到底什麼事?
Captain, what do you want?
叫我杜德利就好
Call me Dudley.
杜德利  你有什麼事?
Dudley what do you want?
好了  小子
Look, lad,
我很欣賞你拒絕出庭作證
I admire your refusal to testify
還有對朋友的忠心
and your loyalty to your partner.
我很欣賞你這種警察
I admire you as a policeman
而你渾身是勁的蠻勁  更是幹這種工作所必須的
and your adherence to violence as a necessary adjunct to the job.
你整那些打老婆的人的方法令我刮目相看
I'm impressed with your punishment of women-beaters.
你恨他們嗎?  溫德爾
Do you hate them, Wendell?
你到底有什麼事?
What do you want?
這是你的
They're yours.
拿去吧
Take them.
不起訴我了?
There's no bill on me?
有四個證人翻供了
-4 witnesses recanted their testimony.
為什麼呢?  他們回心轉意了
-Why? They had a change of heart.
史丹斯呢?
Stensland?
他完了
Your partner's through.
局長命令下的代罪羔羊
Scapegoat on the Chief's orders.
他只剩一年就可以領退休金了
A year from his pension.
艾斯利?  艾斯利得到他所要的
-Exley! -Exley got what he wanted.
他玩弄權謀的技術比我還高明
As a politician he exceeds even myself.
我們局裏需要艾斯利這樣的聰明人
The Department needs smart men like Exley
也需要像你這樣的硬漢
and direct men like you.
我需要你幫我完成  局長交付給我的一項任務
Look, I need you for an assignment the Chief's given me.
這項任務能勝任的人沒幾個
A duty few men are fit for
而你卻是天生的好手
but you were born for.
你將會在位於市政府的兇殺組工作
You'd be working out of Homicide at City Hall.
兇殺組?
Homicide?
偵辦兇殺命案嗎?
Working cases?
你的才能並不在此  溫德爾
Your talents lie elsewhere, Wendell.
我要你做的工作是要靠力氣的
It's a muscle job.
你聽我的命令行事  不要問東問西的
You'll do as I say and ask no questions.
明白我的意思了嗎?
Do you follow my drift?
一清二楚  長官
In Technicolor, sir.
這兩位是布蘭·卡多和安東尼·楚賓諾
"Meet Tony Brancato and Anthony Trombino
兩位因為米奇·柯漢被捕而水漲船高的大哥
two rising lieutenants in the Mickey Cohen rackets.
總把子進牢去了
With the dapper little gent in prison
誰知道他們能紅到什麼地步呢
who knows how far they'll go.
反正前途無量就是了
The sky's the limit.
好了
Oh, well."
"米奇·柯漢的手下陳屍日落大道 "
這位是杜斯·培金斯
"Meet Deuce Perkins,
米奇·柯漢手下的頭號毒王
Mickey Cohen's narcotics lieutenant.
他會不會是幕後的主使人?
Could he be behind the hits?
是不是他在整合黑社會組織?
Is he consolidating organized crime power?
大概不是
I suppose not.
不過有件事是錯不了的
One thing's for sure:
有人在按部就班地幹掉米奇的手下
"柯漢手下的毒王家中遇害"
而在另一方面呢 據說洛城的警方
Meanwhile, rumor has it the LAPD
已經擺出陣仗要大舉掃除
has set up a not-so-Welcome Wagon to dishearten the criminal element
想接替米奇·柯漢的黑社會份子
from filling the void left by Mickey's absence.
我一旦有進一步消息
When I know more,
一定會告訴親愛的讀者
dear readers, so will you.
秘文權威"噓噓雜誌 "
Off the record, on the q.t and very Hush-Hush."
米奇·柯漢進牢了就沒黑社會
With Mickey Cohen in prison, Los Angeles is organized crime-free.
局長希望能保持這個樣子
The Chief wants to keep it that way.
你在克裏夫蘭也是在道上混的
In Cleveland, you're an organized crime associate
只可惜不太懂我們白道的規矩
in desperate need of re-education in the ways of polite society.
我聽到了一些傳言
I hear things.
譬如那些個暗殺小組
Like those 2-men shooter teams.
他們在屠殺柯漢的手下
They're 86ing Cohen's lieutenants.
你們要我怎麼樣嘛?
What do you want?
我們要你回家去!
We want you to go home.
色情書刊  兄弟們
Picture-book smut, men.
最近在犯案現場老是可以找到這玩意兒
There's been a bunch of this found at crime scenes lately.
水準參差不齊
Quality ranges from piss-poor to very well done.
你們看誰復職回來了
Look who's back from suspension.
我們真是三生有幸  傑克警官
We're honored, Sergeant Jack.
你們看  1953年的大爛案
Look at that. The Great Jerk-Off Case of 1953.
你有更好的地方可以去嗎?
Is there someplace you'd rather be?
有  去掃毒組
Yeah, working Narcotics,
搜尋柯漢遺失的海洛因
looking for Cohen's missing H.
對  如果能夠找到那25磅的毒品
Yeah, finding 25 pounds of heroin
你一定可以風風光光上報了
would get you plenty of ink.
不過或許你應該在血腥聖誕前
You should've thought of that before Bloody Christmas.
就想到這一點  破個大案子
Make a major case.
這是你離開這裏唯一的辦法了
It's the only way you'll get out of here.
解散了  各位
Dismissed, gentlemen.
實事求是  傑克
Go get the facts, Jack.
實事求是
Just the facts.
任君選擇
Whatever you desire.
你好  麻煩你們外送到比佛利山莊來
Hi. I'd like to get a delivery to Beverly Hills.
我好像不認識你
I don't know you.
這電話號碼是我朋友給我的
A friend just gave me this number
我想查查看
and I wanted to find out if
你能不能找本電話簿幫我查個姓名地址
Would you grab a reverse directory and shag a name and address for me?
電話是272239
Crestview-2239.
獨家秘報噓噓雜誌
Hush-Hush, off the record and on the q.t.
西德  我是文生
Sid, it's Vincennes.
傑克  你回到緝毒組了
Jackie, you back on narco?
我正需要一些好題材呢
I need some good copy.
吸毒案是沒有  不過掃黃的倒有一件
I have something going with Vice.
哎唷!好東西要給我了
Something juicy for the Sidster?
我們正在追查一些小電影的製片
Tracking porn. Arty, high-class stuff.
你對法國蘭西王朝了不瞭解?
Know about Fleur-de-Lis?
他們的廣告詞是任君選擇
Slogan's "Whatever you desire."
沒有我從來沒聽說過
No, I've heard burkes.
去幫我找一些吸毒的醜聞來嘛
Get me some narco skinny.
我想要報導的是吸毒案
I want to do an all-hophead issue.
特別是黑人爵士歌星跟電影明星吸毒
Shvartze jazz musicians and movie stars. You like it?
你喜歡這個題材嗎?  傑克  我有空再跟你聊了
I'll talk to you later.
查到什麼了?
-What do you got?
那個號碼沒有登記  長官
-The number's not assigned. Sir.
謝謝你
Thanks, Ginger.
地下電話
A bootleg.
想開一點
Take it easy.
時運不濟  史丹斯
Tough break, Stens.
我們會想念你的
We're going to miss you.
真是太不公平了  史丹斯
Raw deal, Stensland.
打小報告的來了
Here comes the snitch.
實在不好意思  長官
Sorry about that, Lieutenant.
你少惹麻煩  巴德
Stay out of trouble, Bud.
我還有幾小時才要去報到
I got a few hours.
走  我請你喝一杯
I'll buy you a drink.
下次吧  我現在趕著去約會
Rain check. I got a hot date.
對方是誰?  你用什麼名義逮捕她的
Who is she and what did you arrest her for?
這是秘密
It's confidential.
就是經常和文生合作的  那個雜誌社的名字一樣
Like that magazine that Vincennes scams for.
噓噓
Hush-Hush.
我們過一兩天再見了
I'll see you later in the week.
我們到時再去快活  我請客
We'll do the town, on me.
是嗎?我還是帶著皮夾以防萬一
Yeah. I'll bring my wallet just in case.
明天見了
-See you tomorrow.
等一下
-Hold on!
我跟你一起走
I'll walk down with you.
小毛頭  他想做給誰看
Punk kid. Who is he trying to impress?
對呀!我也在懷疑
Yeah, I wonder.
不過他倒是官運亨通
Got himself a real career going.
威廉警官請接無線電
Sergeant Williams, pick up, please.
威廉警官
Sergeant Williams?
兇殺組有沒有人在?
Is there anybody up there in Homicide?
到底有沒有人在?
Anybody there?
我是艾斯利警官
Lieutenant Exley.
市中心發生兇殺案了
You've got a homicide downtown.
在夜貓子咖啡廳
-The Nite Owl Coffee Shop.
我知道了
-I got it.
長官  至少死了一個人
At least one person's dead.
我路過想進去喝一杯咖啡
I stopped for coffee.
不許任何人從這個門出來
No one comes through the front door. Understand?
- 明白嗎?  - 明白
- Understand? - Yes，sir
在街道兩頭設立路障  絕對
I want barricades at both ends of the street. Make sure--
電話是我接的  案子是我的
I took the call. It's my case.
你不會想接這個案子的
You don't want it
案子也不會是你的
and you can't have it.
電話是我接的
I took the call.
案子是我的
It's mine.
我派你當副手好了
I'll make you my second-in-command.
組長  請到這邊來一下  到那邊去
Captain, over here, please.
任何人都不許進出
No body allowed inside.
廚子曾開過槍
The cook drew a gun and set it off.
其它人死在男廁所
The rest died in the men's room.
長官  我們找到了十五發散彈鎗彈殼
Sir we got a total of 15 spent 12-gauge Remington shotgun shells.
我猜兇手有三人  手持一次裝填五發的散彈鎗
I'm betting 3 men, 5-shot capacity pumps,
子彈射完剛好十五發
all of them emptying once.
對不起  長官  我們認出一名死者的身份了
Excuse me, we got an I.D. on one of the victims.
是狄克·史丹斯蘭
It's Dick Stensland.
我一開始以為她是麗泰·海華
At first, I thought she was Rita Hayworth.
對  我也是
Yeah, me too.
真是逃過牢獄之災的好方法
Hell of a way to avoid prison.
發生什麼事了?
What happened?
好像是有三個人搶劫咖啡廳
Appears 3 men held up a coffee shop.
收銀員拿出了手槍所以兇手把他給殺了
The guy at the register pulled a.38, so they killed him.
然後再把店裏的人殺個精光
Then they killed everyone else.
長官  夜貓子那件命案可以認屍了
Lieutenant, we're ready with that Nite Owl I.D.
她是你女兒嗎?
Is this your daughter?
我不知道
I don't know.
我們知道這很不容易
We know this is difficult.
你慢慢來
Take your time.
她好像是我的蘇珊
It seems like my Susan.
可是我的蘇珊是金髮不是紅髮
But my Susan was a blonde, not a redhead.
你上次見到她是什麼時候?
When was the last time you saw her?
就是聖誕節之前
Just before Christmas.
我們吵了一架  我不喜歡她的男友
We'd fought. I didn't like her boyfriend.
雷佛太太
Mrs. Lefferts
你女兒有沒有任何特別的記號
does your daughter have any distinguishing marks?
你弄錯了  先生  我很好
You got the wrong idea, mister. I'm fine.
她大腿旁邊有個胎記
She has a birthmark on her hip.
是她沒錯  我的寶貝
It's her. My baby!
節哀順變  雷佛太太
I'm sorry, Mrs. Lefferts.
誰負責偵辦的?
Who's in charge of this investigation?
史密斯組長以及我本人  怎麼了?
Captain Smith and myself. Why?
"夜貓子大屠殺 "
"The Nite Owl Massacre."
儘管口氣誇張了點
Hyperbole aside
這樣的大案子卻非得迅速破案才行
this is a heinous crime that requires swift resolution.
死了六個人
Six victims.
其中一個還是我們自己人  狄克·史丹斯蘭
One of them, one of our own. Dick Stensland.
他是夜貓子的常客
He was a Nite Owl regular,
挑錯了時間  走錯了地方
in the wrong place at the wrong time.
動機似乎是搶劫
Robbery is the likely motive.
由櫃檯上的手套印  以及初步的監識結果看來
We have rubber glove smears on the register and forensics
兇手的確是三個人沒錯
tend toward a trio of shooters.
而且我們已經有了重要線索了
We do have one hot lead.
有人看見三個黑人青少年
Three Negro juveniles
在葛瑞菲斯公園拿著散彈鎗亂射
were seen discharging shotguns in Griffith Park.
有位公園管理員認出他們  開著一部48至50年
A park ranger I.D.'d them as driving a 1948-1950 Mercury coupe
的福特褐紅色雙門跑車
maroon in color.
一小時前警員問到一位賣報的
An hour ago a canvassing crew found a news vendor
他說在深夜一點的時候
who saw a maroon Merc coupe parked
看見褐紅色水星雙門跑車停在夜貓子門口
by the Nite Owl at 1 a.m.
監理處已經整理出  水星雙門車的車主記錄了
DMV has come up with a registration list of Merc coupes.
二人一組每組查訪三位車主
局內的偵訊工作由艾斯利負責
Interrogations will be led by Lt. Edmund Exley.
別吵了
Enough on that!
各位  去把兇手給我抓回來
Gentlemen, just go out and get them.
動用所有必要的警力
Use all necessary force.
這是洛杉磯市民的命令
The people of Los Angeles demand it.
解散
Dismissed.
直接懸賞他們的人頭不更乾脆
Why not just put a bounty on them?
可以走了嗎  懷特?
-Ready to roll?
你自己去就好了  我另外有事
-You take them, I got something to do.
萬一正好就是那三個
What if one of these names--?
找別人跟你去
Get somebody else.
名單拿到了
I got our assignments, Big V.
照這份名單找下去一輩子也找不到
We go by this list, we got zero chance of making this collar.
我有位線人對傑佛遜街以南很熟
I got a guy who knows what happens south of Jefferson.
他可以幫我們抓到人
He'll put us at 50-50.
傑克  你幹什麼?
What are you doing?
你上一次就是這樣子才惹上一身麻煩的
It's the same sort of thing that got you in trouble before.
我就跟你冒這個險
I'll take those odds.
現在開始由我們來
We got it from here.
你們應該隨身帶著攝影記者的
You two should bring along a photographer.
我想查一下你一位顧客的地址
I need an address on a customer of yours.
她的名字叫琳恩
Her name is Lynn.
你就丟給我這麼個名字?
-That's all I got to go on?
對
-Yeah.
你很清楚我是什麼人  所以上道一點吧!
You already know who I mean, so cough it up.
上頭有收帳跟送貨的地址
There's a billing address and a delivery address.
你是皮爾斯·巴卻嗎?
Are you Pierce Patchett?
是
I am.
你是來勸募警察福利基金的嗎?
Are you soliciting for police charities?
上一次是你打電話來的吧?
Last time you called my office.
到下面的車庫  我們到那兒談
Go on down to the driveway. We'll talk there.
你有什麼事?
What can I do for you?
你昨晚在哪裏?
-Where were you last night?
在這裏舉行晚宴
-I was here hosting a party.
把狄克·史丹斯蘭的事告訴我
Tell me about Dick Stensland.
我不認識他  你是
I don't know him, Mr.--?
懷特警員
Officer White.
你認識蘇珊雷佛嗎?
You know Sue Lefferts?
你知道我認識的  你看見我跟她在一起的
You know I do. You saw me with her.
你怎麼找到我的?
How did you find me?
尼克的烈酒商店
Nick's Liquor.
是琳恩·佈雷肯寫的收帳地址
This is where Lynn Bracken's booze bills go.
對哦!
Of course.
蘇珊雷佛在夜貓子死了
Sue Lefferts died at the Nite Owl.
我正在調查這件案子
I'm investigating.
沒什麼事吧?  巴卻先生
Everything all right?
沒事  謝謝你
Fine, Phillip, thank you.
你另外那個保鏢巴茲呢?
What happened to the other guy, Buzz?
巴茲·米克斯已經不替我工作了
Buzz Meeks no longer works for me.
雷佛在聖誕夜似乎被打了
Lefferts looked beat-up Christmas Eve
可是她卻沒報案  為什麼?
but didn't act it. Why?
我想她是被網球拍打到的
I think she'd been hit in the face with a tennis racket.
她很喜歡打雙打
She was a big doubles fan.
你是命案死者的友人
You're a known associate of a woman killed in a mass murder.
要不要到局裏去跟我們談?
-Want to go downtown to discuss this?
只是為了這件事嗎  警察先生
-Is this official?
我怎麼覺得你似乎是為了個人的私事來找我的
Somehow I have the feeling this is more personal with you.
好了
All right, then
你現在是奉命調查跟命案有關的事情嗎?
are you concerned about criminal matters peripheral to the murders?
目前沒有  那你不見得要向上級報告羅?
-Not at the moment. -You're not obligated to report them?
為什麼雷佛臉上會有淤血?
Why were Lefferts' eyes black?
我需要一位麗泰·海華來充實我影棚的陣容
I needed a Rita Hayworth to fill out my little studio.
什麼影棚?
What little studio?
我們那兒有很多像電影明星的女孩
Well, there's Gardner, Russell, Monroe, Turner.
琳恩是我的薇洛尼卡.雷克
Lynn Bracken is my Veronica Lake.
我專找長的像電影明星的女孩
I use girls that look like movie stars.
有時難免得稍微整容一下
Sometimes I employ a plastic surgeon.
那晚正好被你看見了
When the work was done, that's when you saw us.
所以她老母認不出她來
It's why her mom couldn't I.D. her.
我的老天啊!
Jesus fucking Christ!
我不是老天  我是皮爾斯·巴卻
No, Pierce Morehouse Patchett.
我知道你職責在身
I sense you're on your best behavior,
可是我言盡於此
but that's all I'm saying.
如果你再追問下去我只好找律師來了
If you persist, we'll meet with my attorney.
你要不要琳恩的地址?我想她似乎不
Would you like Lynn Bracken's address?
我已經有她的地址了
I got her address.
找出殺死蘇珊的人  懷特先生
Find Susan's killer, Mr. White.
我會給你一大筆獎金的
I'll give you a handsome reward.
任君選擇
Whatever you desire!
我知道你還沒睡
I know you're not asleep.
你是在跟我說話嗎?
What do you want?
你要什麼?  我的五塊錢
My 5 bucks.
我就這麼些錢了
It was the only one I had.
現在?
Right now?
喂  寶貝  叫他別來騷擾我們
Hey, doll face, tell him to leave us alone.
我瞭解
I understand.
好的
Okay, fine.
哦!寶貝
Oh, baby
壞消息
bad news.
你得走了
You have to go.
走?
Go?
有很重要的事發生了  所以你得走了  不過
Something very important has come up and you have to go.
我改天會補償你的  好嗎?
I'll make it up to you.
我會的  我保證
I will, I promise.
讓我過去
Excuse me.
是警察嗎?
Is it the cops?
佈雷肯小姐
Miss Bracken
我是懷特警員
I'm Officer White.
我知道你要來
I've been expecting you,
只是沒想到這麼快
just not this soon.
皮爾斯來過電話  把蘇珊的遭遇告訴我了
Pierce called. He told me what happened to Sue.
沒什麼麻煩吧  寶貝?
Everything all right, doll?
要不要我把他攆走?
Want me to get rid of him?
上路吧  兄弟
Hit the road.
說不定我會走
Maybe I will
也說不定我不走
maybe I won't.
我是洛城警察  快點滾開
LAPD. Get out of here
否則我叫你太太來抓你了
or I'll have your wife come get you.
警員  議員
-Officer. -Councilman.
要不要來杯酒?
-Would you care for a drink?
好  純威士忌
-Yeah, Scotch straight.
我跟蘇珊還挺不錯的
I was friendly with Sue Lefferts,
不過我們不是朋友
but we weren't friends.
你明白我的意思嗎?
Know what I mean?
她死了你會難過嗎?
You sorry she's dead?
當然會
Of course I am.
這算哪門子問題?
What kind of question is that?
你知道皮爾斯為什麼這樣子耍你嗎?
Do you know why Pierce is humoring you?
你用耍這個字會把我惹毛的
Use words like that, you might make me mad.
不過你知不知道為什麼?
But, do you know?
我知道
Yeah, I know.
他讓女孩整容變得像電影明星
Patchett's running whores
然後替他賣淫
cut to look like movie stars.
而從他的豪宅看來
And, judging by his address,
他另外還有更大的買賣
something bigger on the side.
所以不希望太過出風頭
He doesn't want any attention.
沒錯  我們的動機很自私
That's right. Our motives are selfish
不過我們會合作的
so we're cooperating.
那就合作吧  佈雷肯小姐!  蘇珊為什麼去夜貓子?
So cooperate. Why was Susan Lefferts at the Nite Owl?
我不知道!  這是我第一次聽到夜貓子這個名字
I don't know. I never heard of the Nite Owl till today.
她是怎麼認識皮爾斯的?
How'd she meet Patchett?
皮爾斯交遊很廣
Pierce meets people.
蘇珊則滿懷明星夢
Sue had dreams of Hollywood
如今卻落得這個下場
and this is how they turned out.
全拜皮爾斯之賜
Thanks to Pierce,
我們依然得繼續裝下去
we still get to act a little.
告訴我皮爾斯的底細吧
Tell me about Pierce.
他還在等你向他開價呢?
He's waiting for you to mention money.
要不要聽聽我的建議?佈雷肯小姐
Want advice, Miss Bracken?
叫我琳恩
It's Lynn.
佈雷肯小姐
Miss Bracken
千萬不要想要賄賂我
don't ever try to fucking bribe me
否則我他媽的整得你跟皮爾斯叫苦連天
or I'll have you and Patchett in shit up to your ears.
聖誕夜那天的事深印在我腦中
I remember you from Christmas Eve.
你一向很喜歡幫女人對不對?
You have a thing for helping women, don't you?
說不定我只是他媽的好奇而已
Maybe I'm just fucking curious.
你一天到晚把髒話掛在嘴上
-You say "fuck" a lot.
你卻一天到晚為了錢在操人
-You fuck for money.
你的襯衫上有血
There's blood on your shirt.
是不是幹員警就得打人?
An integral part of your job?
對  你喜歡打人嗎?
-Yeah. -Do you enjoy it?
如果對方欠揍的話
When they deserve it.
他們今天欠揍嗎?
Did they deserve it today?
我不知道
I'm not sure.
可是你還是揍人了
-But you did it anyway.
對
-Yeah.
就像你今天接了十幾個人一樣
Like the half dozen guys you screwed today.
事實上只有兩個
Actually, it was only two.
你真是與眾不同  懷特警官
You're different, Officer White.
五年來你是第一個
You're the first man in years
沒說我很像薇洛妮卡的人
who didn't tell me I look like Veronica Lake.
你比她漂亮
You look better than Veronica Lake.
皮爾斯他?
Pierce Patchett?
他會把我們賺的抽一部份
He takes a cut of our earnings
去替我們投資理財
and invests it for us.
他不許我們吸毒  也不會打我們
He doesn't let us use narcotics and he doesn't abuse us.
你們警察能想像得到這種矛盾的做法嗎?
Can your policeman's mentality grasp those contradictions?
他讓你去整得像薇洛妮卡的?
He had you cut to look like Veronica Lake.
不
No.
我本來是黑髮  其它的都沒變
I'm really a brunette, but the rest is me.
你只要知道這些就夠了
And that's all the news that's fit to print.
很高興認識你
It's nice meeting you.
我想再跟你見面
-I'd like to see you again.
你這是在約我嗎?
-For a date
還是在跟我預約時間?
or an appointment?
我不知道
I don't know.
如果是約會  那你該告訴我你的名字
-For a date, I'd know your first name.
忘了我剛剛說的話
-Forget I asked.
是我說錯話了
It was a mistake.
雷歐那比威爾嗎?
Leonard Bidwell?
下來聊聊吧
Come down here and talk to us.
最近左拳練得怎麼樣?
How's the left these days?
這關你什麼事?
What's it to you?
我看過你跟佳威蘭小子打拳
I saw you fight Kid Gavilan.
我很喜歡你的拳風
I like your style.
你有什麼事?警察先生
What do you want, Mr. Policeman?
你有個兄弟關在佛森監獄
You got a brother in Folsom.
我知道  是我把他關進去的
I put him there.
他得關到1970年
Until 1970.
你希不希望只關到1960年
How'd you like to make it 1960?
我認識那位法官副組長是檢察官的好朋友
I know the judge, and Lieutenant Exley is good friends with the D.A.
好了  我們在找三個愛玩散彈鎗的黑人
We're looking for 3 colored guys who like to shoot shotguns.
其中一個開著褐紅色的跑車
One owns a maroon Mercury coupe.
你想害我背上罪人的名字
-Want me to snitch?
你想不想幫你哥哥減個十年
-Want to buy your brother 10 years?
是十年對不對?
-It was 10 years, right?
對  十年
-Yeah, 10 years.
你用不著開口
You don't have to say anything,
只要看看名單  用手指就行了
just look at this list and point.
那傢伙很壞所以我直接告訴你
He's bad, so I'll just tell you.
蜜糖雷伊柯林斯
Sugar Ray Collins.
開著一部49年的福特跑車
Drives a maroon '49 coupe.
車子很漂亮
Beautiful ride.
有沒有散彈鎗我不知道
Don't know about shotguns,
不過他一向以殺狗為樂
but he gets his thrills killing dogs.
他是標準的垃圾
He's righteous trash.
你看看  離這兒才五分鐘
Look at that. It's five minutes from here.
謝謝你
Thanks.
你會給我消息吧?
I'll hear from you
我哥哥的事
about my brother?
手抬高一點  雷尼  抬高一點
Keep it up, Lenny. U p!
到了  在後面
There it is. It's in the back.
自己人的車  該死
-One of ours. -Shit,
有人想趕在我們的前面
somebody beat us here!
該死  我的眼鏡
Damn it! My glasses!
你開什麼玩笑
You're kidding!
反正別朝我開槍就是了
Well, just don't shoot me.
你們來做什麼?
What are you doing here?
我們正好在這附近
We were in the neighborhood.
查到什麼了? 三把十二發的散彈鎗
-What do you got? -Three 12-gauge pumps.
空的子彈盒  還有一些現金
And cash.
再見了  掃黃組
So long, Vice. Badge of Honor,
警網群英  我來了
here I come.
去你的  這機會是我們的
Fuck you! This is our collar.
安靜!
Quiet!
這兒我官階最高
I'm ranking officer here.
我們合作抓人  不用再爭了
We go as a team. End of story.
好
Right.
有幾個人口?
How many ways in?
只有一個  從樓梯上去
Only one. Up the stairs.
他是很認真的
He's very serious.
我們是警察!  搞什麼? 不要開槍
Police! Don't shoot!
別動
-Don't move.
殺了他  傑克  閉嘴  布魯尼
-Ace him, Jack! Shut up.
很緊張吧?
Anxious, aren't you?
不要殺他們
Don't kill them.
退回去  退回去
Back, back, back!
你放開我
Get off me!
面對著牆站好
Against the wall!
把雙手舉起來
-Put your hands up!
過來  孩子  快點
-Get over there.
閉嘴  把手放在背後
Shut up! Hands behind your back!
怎樣?  走出辦公室的感覺如何
So how's it feel getting out of the office?
這是監識組來的報告
This came from forensics.
他們在燒衣服
"Burning clothes.
卡西達少年監獄
Casitas Youth Camp."
這兒挺擠的  懷特
It's crowded in here, White.
他們殺死了史丹斯蘭
These guys killed Stensland.
這些彈殼上面的彈道痕跡
The ejection marks on the shells fired from the shotguns
跟我們在夜貓子找到的彈殼是一樣的
are identical to those on the shell casings found at the Nite Owl.
我要他們坦白招供  埃德蒙
I want confessions, Edmund.
熬了一晚他們應該已經軟化了
A night's stewing has softened them up.
我會瓦解他們心理防線的
I'll break them, sir.
你確定我們金童干的來嗎?
Are you sure golden boy is up to the task, Cap?
我想你會被他的能耐嚇一跳的
I think you'd be surprised what the lad is capable of.
你今年22歲對不對?
You're 22. Aren't you, Ray?
有沒有警察修理過你?
Did an officer work you over?
你今年22歲對不對?
-You're 22, right?
你為什麼一直這樣子問我?
-Why do you keep asking that?
因為滿22歲就可以判死刑
所以你應該十年前殺人才對的
You should've pulled this caper years ago.
判個終生監禁  在少年感化院關到21歲
Get life, do a little Youth Authority jolt
再轉到佛森監獄去
transfer to Folsom a big man
找個愛人同志
get yourself a sissy.
我不搞同性戀那一套的
I don't truck with no sissies.
路易斯
Louis.
幹嘛?
What?
你跟路易斯兩個人  在卡西達一起坐過牢對不對?
You did the Casitas Youth Camp with Louis.
你為什麼一直問我路易斯的事情?
Why you keep asking me about Louis?
他的事跟我無關
His business is his business.
蜜糖  路易斯跟我說你在卡西達搞過同性戀
Sugar, Louis told me you went sissy up at Casitas.
你熬不下去了
You couldn't do the time,
所以找了個白人男孩來照顧你
so you got a big white boy to look after you.
他們還說他們會管你叫蜜糖
Said they called you "Sugar"
是因為你對愛人同志很甜
because you gave it out so sweet.
路易斯他才獻出了玻璃呢
Louis gave it up at Casitas.
我在我們牢房是老大
I was the boss jock in my dorm!
路易斯才是愛人同志
Louis was the sissy!
路易斯為棒棒糖就獻身了
Louis gave it up for candy bars!
他簡直比狗還笨
He isn't got the sense of a dog!
聽說你很喜歡殺狗
You like to shoot dogs.
狗沒有資格活
Dogs got no reason to live.
你對人也有同樣的感覺嘛?
Feel the same way about people?
你到底想說什麼嘛?
What're you trying to say?
我們搜到散彈鎗了
We got the shotguns.
我根本沒有什麼散彈鎗的
I don't own no shotguns.
你們為什麼把衣服拿去燒呢?
Why were you throwing clothes in the incinerator?
你說什麼?
Say what?
有鄰居說看見你們把衣服拿去焚化爐燒
A neighbor said she saw you throwing clothes in the incinerator.
這樣子可不太妙
Doesn't look good.
沒見到法官之前我不會再說話了
I isn't talking till I see a judge.
你是不是吸了毒了?
Were you on hop?
我們逮捕你的時候你已經攤在那兒
You were passed out when we arrested you.
泰依跟路易斯才會吸那玩意兒
Ty and Louis fuck with that shit, not me.
我不會  他們在哪兒弄到貨的?
Where do they get their stuff?
快點  給我個人向檢察官交待
Man. Give me one to feed the D.A.
這樣子我臉上好看一點
It'll make me look good
那我相信你不是同性戀
and I'll say Sugar Ray's not a punk like his sissy partners.
好了  雷蒙
All right.
多說一點路易斯和泰依的事
Tell me one more thing about Jones and Fontaine.
他們在哪兒弄到毒品的?
Where do they get drugs?
羅蘭那法瑞那兒
Roland Navarette.
他在木屋山莊那兒有個據點
He runs a hole-up on Bunker Hill.
而且還賣紅魔鬼
And he sells red devils.
艾斯利很行  我服了他了
Exley's good, I'll give him that.
我要去休息一下了
I'll take a break.
對了  雷依
You know, Ray,
我都說你可能被送進毒氣室了
I'm talking about the gas chamber
可是你卻一直沒有問我  我們到底在查什麼案子
and you haven't asked me what this is about.
你是跳到黃河都洗不清了
You got a big "guilty" sign around your neck.
真是技術高超  埃德蒙
That was masterful, Edmund.
他已經準備好要招供了
He's ready to go.
拿份報紙給路易斯
Give Jones the newspaper.
我要他跳起來
I want him primed.
把手銬拿掉好讓他看報
Take the cuffs off, so he can read it.
雷依剛剛出賣你了
Ray Collins just ratted you off.
他說夜貓子那件事是你帶頭的
Said the Nite Owl was your idea.
我覺得是雷依帶頭的
I think it was Ray's idea.
你要是招出來我想我可以救你一命
You talk, I think I can save your life.
死了六個人啊
總得有人頂罪吧!
and someone has to pay for it.
那個人可以是你  也可以是雷依
Now, it can be you, or it can be Ray.
路易斯  他說你是同性戀的
Louis, he called you queer.
還說你在卡西達被玩的很厲害
-At Casitas, you took it up the ass.
我根本沒有殺人
-I didn't kill nobody!!
孩子
Son
你很清楚如果不招出來會有什麼下場
you know what'll happen if you don't talk.
你會被送去毒氣室所以你還是招了吧
You'll go to the gas chamber. So admit what you did.
我並不想傷害她
I didn't mean to hurt her.
說不定她沒事呢?
-Maybe she's okay.
沒事?
-Okay?
他們全在停屍間了
They're all in the morgue.
你走的時候他們就已經全死了
They were dead when you left them.
我只不過是想要開苞而已嘛
I just wanted to lose my cherry.
她沒死的話我也就不用死了
She don't die, so I don't die.
她沒死所以我也不用死
路易斯  那個女孩是誰?
Louis, who's the girl?
她叫什麼名字?
What's her name?
你到底在說什麼?
Who are you talking about?
她是不是在夜貓子那兒?
Was she at the Nite Owl?
路易斯  聽我說她是不是在夜貓子那兒?
Listen to me, was she at the Nite Owl?
這份報紙在胡說八道
-This paper shit isn't shit!
路易斯說的那個女孩在哪裏?
-Where's the girl?
你們殺了她嗎?
You kill her?
你們本來只是要讓路易斯開苞
Louis lost his cherry,
可是你們覺得還不過癮結果事情鬧得太過份了
but things got out of hand.
你們就打了那個女孩
You made her bleed.
她的血濺到你們的衣服上面
She bled on your clothes,
所以你們把衣服燒了
so you burned the clothes.
誰說的?
Who said that?!
你給我聽好
Now, listen to me.
如果她還活著的話
If she's alive,
她是你們活命的唯一機會了
she's the only chance you've got.
我想她還活著  你想?
-I think she's alive. -You think?
那她在那裏?
Where is she now?
你們是不是把她丟哪裏?  還是把她賣了?
Did you leave her someplace?
告訴我她在哪裏?
Where is she?
你在幹什麼?
What're you doing?
懷特
White!
六分之一的機會
她在哪裏?
Where's the girl?!
懷特  我已經控制住狀況了
Put the weapon down!
把槍放下來  那個女孩在哪裏?
Where's the girl?!!
希維思特之家
Sylvester Fitch
什麼?
What?
希維思特之家  艾瓦龍街109號
Sylvester Fitch, 109 Avalon
樓上角落的棕色房間
brown corner house, upstairs.
給我一分鐘的時間
-Just give me one minute.
沒有問題
-You got it.
大家先別動
Nobody moves.
我們幾個從前門進去
We're going in the front.
在我下令之前先別動
Stay put until I give the word.
他繞到後面去了
He went around back!
我是艾斯利副組長
I'm Lieutenant Exley.
對不起  這麼問你
I'm sorry to ask you this.
我需要知道他們什麼時候丟下你的
I need to know when they left you.
把她送到醫院去
Get her to the hospital.
借過一下
Excuse me.
別一直急著陞官
Give your career a rest.
別去煩她
Leave her alone.
一絲不掛的男人會用槍射你?
A naked guy with a gun?
你認為會有人相信嗎?
Who'll believe that?
你離我遠一點
Get the fuck away from me.
你的報告寫出來會是什麼樣子
How'll it look in your report?
會像正義得到伸張
It'll look like justice.
這正是那個男人的下場
That's what the man got.
接受正義的制裁
Justice.
你根本不知道正義兩個字是什麼意思
You don't know the meaning of the word.
是嗎?  你以為你的照片上報才叫做正義嗎?
You think it means getting your picture in the paper.
你要找  去找壞人的麻煩
Go after criminals for a change.
別老是找警察的麻煩
instead of cops
史丹斯蘭他是活該  你也是
Stensland got what he deserved and so will you.
別那麼衝動  巴德
come on, bud
他那麼沖  你最好是離他遠一點
It's best to stay away when his blood is up.
他永遠是那麼沖的
His blood's always up.
或許你永遠都不應該靠近他
Perhaps you should stay away from him altogether.
逃犯雷蒙克林斯  泰依瓊斯和路易斯方騰
Raymond Collins, Ty Jones and Louis Fontaine.
擁有槍械極為危險
They are considered armed and dangerous.
重複 夜貓子案的嫌犯脫逃了
Repeat. The Nite Owl suspects have escaped.
他們怎麼爬出窗戶去的?
How'd they get out the window?
我們只知道他們從二樓跳下去
They jumped from the 2nd floor.
醫院那個女孩做好筆錄了  說他們在十二點丟下她的
Girl said they left her at 12.
他們很有可能在一點左右到了夜貓子那兒
They could get to the Nite Owl by 1.
問題是他們那兒弄到毒品的
The question was, where did they get their drugs?
我還沒有想到那兒去呢
I haven't gotten that far yet.
羅蘭·那法瑞在木屋街有個據點
"Roland Navarette lives on Bunker Hill,
各種毒品甚至連紅魔鬼都有
runs a hole-up"
有沒有人看見傑克·文生?
Anyone seen Jack Vincennes?
有什麼事嗎?
Is something up?
我需要人支持  走
I need some backup. Go
怎麼了?  沒事  走吧
-What? -Nothing. Let's go.
應該就是這了
This should be it.
通通不許動
Nobody moves!
不要動  你們被捕了
You're under arrest.
不要開槍
Don't shoot, man!
手舉起來  別動
Don't move! Don't move!
他來了
There he is.
你表現的很好  孩子
You did good, kid.
你應該看看那個地方的到處都是血  像場惡夢
You should've seen this place. Blood everywhere.
真是沒想到  散彈艾德!
Who would have thought? Shotgun Ed.
對  散彈艾德
Yes. Shotgun Ed.
誰帶他去包紮一下吧
Somebody get him cleaned up.
走吧  孩子
Come on.
夜貓子屠殺案的破案英雄
埃德蒙艾斯利在洛杉磯警局服務了七年
Edmund J. Exley has amassed a brilliant record
當中表現異常優異
in his 7 years with the Los Angeles Police Department.
最近在執勤的時候更是表現的非常英勇
Recently, he evinced spectacular bravery in the line of duty.
所以我們深感榮幸  能夠頒發給他我們的最高榮譽
It is our privilege to present him with our highest honor:
勇士獎章
The Medal of Valor.
那是什麼車子?
-What kind of car was it? -It was a Ford.
福特的  你確定嗎?
Ford. Are you sure?
我先生總是開福特
My husband always drove a Ford.
所以我知道福特的樣子
I know what they look like.
對不起夫人  說重點就好了
Excuse me, ma'am. Just the facts.
是淺色還是暗色的?  淺色的
Light or dark? Light.
我真的只記得這些了  警官
And that's really all I remember, Officer.
謝謝你  你幫了我們大忙
Thank you. You've been a big help.
卡  拿去沖印吧
Cut! That's a print.
大傑克  他回來了
Big Jack! He's back!
傑克回來了
Jack's back.
告訴巴卻先生我不會改變的
Tell Mr. Patchett I have no intention of changing my vote.
有的人或許會感到驚訝
It may surprise some that
一個政治人物竟然能勇於認錯
an official would admit to making a mistake
可是經過深思熟慮以後
but after due consideration
我決定改變對此事的立場
I am changing my position on the matter before the council.
"西進吧  美國!  "
"Go west, America,"
是當年政府的偉大號召
was a slogan of Manifest Destiny.
今天西進步伐將完成最後一步
Today is that last step westward with no stop signs
因為從市中心一直到海邊
no traffic signals, from downtown
二十分鐘的路程沿途沒有任何的紅綠燈
to the beach in 20 minutes.
你想從那一行幹起?
What were you going to start with?
綠燈戶?
Prostitution?
賭場?
Gambling?
回新澤西去吧  孩子
Go back to Jersey, sonny.
這裏是天使之城
This is the City of the Angels
而你身上沒有翅膀
and you haven't got any wings.
改天見  保重
Nice to see you again. Take care.
我一直在想  你什麼時候會再來找我  懷特警員
I wondered when you'd knock on my door again, Officer White.
叫我巴德
It's Bud.
巴德
Bud.
為什麼選上我?
Why me?
我不知道
I don't know.
這一次的選舉
This election
關繫著洛城警局的未來
is about the future of law enforcement in Los Angeles.
而羅傑議員正代表著我們美好的未來
City Councilman Rogers represents that future.
所以請大家慷慨解囊
So let's dig deep
協助一個高尚正直的人當選
and get a moral man re-elected.
我們現在歡迎艾利斯羅來說幾句話
Ellis Loew wants to say a few words.
謝謝你  佈雷特雀斯
Thank you, Brett Chase.
警網群英中傑出的大明星
The talented star of Badge of Honor.
我可以告訴各位
Let me tell you,
我今天能夠站在這裏覺得非常的榮幸
I am so thrilled to be here.
大文·傑克
Big V.
很高興看到你回來了
Good to see you back.
最近勇猛十足吧
-How they hanging, Sid?
都舉不起頭來了
-Down around my ankles.
你跟檢察官很熟嗎?  傑克
You tight with the D.A., Jackie?
很熟
Yes.
他去年聖誕節還想讓我走路呢
Yeah. He tried to throw me off the force last Christmas.
想不想好好報個仇?
How about some payback, big-time?
另外我照常捐五十塊錢給傑克·文生的退休基金
Plus the usual 50 dollar donation to the Jack Vincennes retirement fund.
你知道檢察官他是同性戀嗎?
-Did you know the D.A. was a swish?
真的嗎?
-No kidding?
你還記得麥特·雷諾嗎?
Remember Matt Reynolds? Christmas Eve?
去年的耶誕夜大明星首映場被捕
"The Movie Premiere Pot Bust"?
他剛剛服完獄外役回來
-He just got off the honor farm.
那他到這兒來幹什麼?
-What's he doing here?
雷諾是個雙性戀
Reynolds is acey-deucey,
如果有錢賺當然更起勁
not to mention broke.
我給了他一百塊錢讓他跟檢察官搞
I'm getting him to fuck the D.A. for $100.
比你毀了他演藝生涯的酬勞還要多一倍
That's twice the $50 you got for wrecking his career.
過來
-Come here, come here.
天哪!不要叫他過來
-Jesus, don't bring him--
那邊那位就是羅檢察官
That's D.A. Loew right there.
好
Ok.
要不要先喝杯酒
You need a drink?
要
Yeah.
照顧他一下
Look after him.
麥特  這位是傑克
Matt, this is Jack.
我們之間沒有什麼秘密
No secrets between me and him.
你好嗎? 我很好  你呢?
-How you doing? -I'm okay. How're you?
很好
I'm good.
我們以前有沒有見過面?
Have we met before?
有
Yeah.
是在宴會上嗎?
Was it at a party?
跟今天的場合差不多
It was something like that.
法蘭西王朝的宴會對吧?
Fleur-de-Lis party, right?
對
Right.
法蘭西王朝
Fleur-de-Lis.
任君選擇
"Whatever you desire."
毒品  長的像電影明星的女郎
Dope, hookers that look like movie stars.
皮爾斯·巴卻全都一應俱全
Pierce Patchett has it all.
真是一點都沒錯
You could say that again.
皮爾斯跟其它的人不太一樣
Pierce, he's not like regular guys.
我很喜歡他  不過
I dig him, but
你知道的  他也讓我很害怕
you know he scares me too.
真的嗎?
Really?
怎麼會呢?
How?
我剛到洛杉機的時候根本沒想到會變成今天這樣
When I came out to L.A. this isn't exactly where I saw myself ending up.
是啊  大家都一樣
Yeah, well get in line.
壯壯膽吧  孩子  乾杯
Your courage, kid. Drink up.
我看還是不要好了
I don't think I should do this.
你又不是不知道怎麼做?
It's not like you don't know how.
傑克跟警網群英製作很熟的
Jack's connected to Badge of Honor.
事情做好了他會替你爭取個角色的
Pull this off, you'll get a part.
我看有人要東山再起了對不對  傑克?
I smell a comeback, don't you, Jack?
檢察官他有空了
The D.A.'s free.
去自我介紹一下  快點
Go introduce yourself. Go on.
你說話啊  傑克告訴他你會替他爭取的
Tell him about the opening on the show.
對  我有把握可以讓你上節目
I'm pretty sure I can get you a part on this show.
不過那是以後的事了
But that's later on.
今晚你應該假裝你是在演戲
Tonight, go on over there and pretend it's an acting job.
這也是演藝事業的一種
Like show biz.
演戲  沒錯
Acting, that's it.
對  沒有人會知道對不對?
Right. No one's going to know about this?
沒有
No.
這是我們之間的秘密
It'll be our secret.
好  演藝事業
-Show biz.
對  快去
-That's it. Go on.
演藝事業
Show biz.
如果雷諾施展他的魅力
If Reynolds works his charms,
而我知道他會的
which I know he will
那他們待會應該會在好萊塢中心旅館203房
they'll be at the Hollywood Center Motel, room 203.
子夜的時候到那兒等我好拍照
Meet me there at midnight for a photo shoot.
說不定這一次可以把  好萊塢那個大招牌給照進去
And maybe we can work in the Hollywood sign this time.
你對皮爾巴卻瞭解多少
What do you know about Pierce Patchett?
跟你一樣所知不多
I know what you know.
他很有錢
He's rich.
然後把錢拿去蓋高速公路了  使得它變的更有錢了
Invested in the freeways, which'll make him richer.
你幹嘛問這個?
Why?
我不斷聽到一些謠言
I just keep hearing rumors, you know.
什麼高檔應召站  毒品
High-class porn, drugs,
長的像電影明星的妓女
hookers that look like movie stars.
巴卻是那種不惹眼的人物
Patchett's what I call twilight.
他舉止也不古怪  也不是共產黨
He isn't queer or Red.
根本沒什麼新奇刺激的故事可以讓我寫的
He cannot help me in my quest for prime sinnuendo.
就好像警網群英的製作人不會找那傢伙演戲一樣
As though Badge of Honor would touch that guy with a 10-foot pole
因為他一年當中二度當上我雜誌的封面人物
after he's been Hush-Hush cover boy twice in one year.
待會見
See you soon.
子夜  我保證定會非常緊張刺激的
Midnight. I guarantee all kinds of illegal activity.
再來一杯?  對
Another? Yeah.
好萊塢中心汽車旅館
小子
Kid?
兄弟
Brother.
好了  你犯不著幹這種事
Come on, you don't have to do this--
非常謝謝你為我報仇
Thank you for what you did for me
殺了那些強暴我的禽獸
for killing those animals who raped me.
請你替我謝謝懷特警員好嗎
Will you thank Officer White for me, please?
當然
Sure.
我現在腦海裏只記得  看見他從那個門走過來
Seeing him come through the door is about the only thing I remember.
真是謝天謝地
Thank God.
你還記得那些黑人什麼時候丟下你嗎?
You remember what time the Negroes left you, right?
你在供詞中說
In your statement,
他們是子夜的時候離開你的
you said they left you at midnight.
可能是吧?
They might have.
你這麼說是什麼意思?
They "might" have?
我不知道他們什麼時候離開我
I don't know what time they left me.
我只希望他們死
I wanted them dead.
如果他們沒有殺死夜貓子那些白人
Would anyone care that they raped a Mexican girl
會有任何人在乎  他們強暴了一個墨西哥女孩嗎?
if they hadn't killed those white people at the Nite Owl?
我這一切都是為了報仇
I did what I had to do for justice.
英奈茲
Inez.
艾利斯也在  過來
Exley, over here.
笑一下  英奈茲
Smile, Inez.
他是你的大英雄吧
Is he your hero?
各位  這個標題怎麼樣?
Fellas, how about this?
"夜貓子案英雄推著被害人走出醫院 "
"Rape Victim Wheeled Out by Nite Owl Hero."
他們只得到了薇洛妮卡雷克
All they get is Veronica Lake.
而我得到琳恩瑪格莉特佈雷肯
I get Lynn Margaret Bracken.
比斯比
"Bisbee?"
我在那兒長大的
I grew up there.
我過幾年要回那兒去
I'm going back in a couple of years,
開一家服裝店
open up a dress shop.
比斯比的女孩需要好衣服打扮
The girls in Bisbee need a little glamour.
這疤是怎來的?
Where'd this come from?
我當年十二歲  我爸拿著酒瓶要砸我媽
I was 12. My dad went after my mother with a bottle.
我正好擋在中間
I got in the way.
所以是你救了你媽的?
So you saved her.
也救不了她多久
Not for long.
很對不起  這不關我的事的
-I'm sorry. It's none of my business.
他把我綁在暖氣機上面
-He tied me to the radiator.
我看著他用熨斗把我媽打死
I watched him beat my mother to death with a tire iron
然後他把我丟在那兒
and he left me there.
三天後學校督學才發現我們
Three days before a truant officer found us.
警方一直沒有找到我老頭
They never found the old man.
所以你才當警察的?
Is that why you became a cop?
為了討個公道?
To get even?
或許吧
Maybe.
你喜歡當警察嗎?
Do you like it?
以前喜歡
I used to.
如今這差事卻變成恃強凌弱了
Now it's all strong-arm, sitting duck stuff.
如果
If I could
如果我能有機會到兇殺組去
get a chance to work Homicide
像真正的刑警一樣辦案
like a real detective.
那個痞子艾斯利他殺錯人了
That prick, Exley, he shot the wrong guys.
殺死史丹斯蘭的人還逍遙法外
Whoever killed Stensland's still around.
我內心裏很清楚  我知道
I know it in here. I know it.
夜貓子那件案子不太對勁
Something's wrong with the Nite Owl.
只是我沒辦法證明而已
I just can't prove it, that's all.
我不夠聰明
I'm not smart enough.
我只是上頭長官用來嚇唬別人的工具而已
I'm just the guy they bring in to scare the other guy shitless.
你錯了
You're wrong.
你找到巴卻  你找到了我
You found Patchett. You found me.
你已經夠聰明了
You're smart enough.
巴德·懷特  什麼風把你吹到地下室來的?
Bud White! What brings you down to the basement?
我有幾個夜貓子案的問題想要問你
I got a couple of Nite Owl questions.
不知道你有沒有看過報紙
Don't know if you read the papers,
那個案子已經結了
but that case is closed.
你有沒有那裏覺得不對勁的
Anything bother you about it?
有  就是那些送貨的  還沒把這些東西給抬走
The fact that the pack-up boys haven't hauled this shit out of here yet.
我們查到嫌犯的三把散彈鎗彈道跟夜貓子的彈殼一致
The suspects' 3 shotguns match the strike marks on the shell casings.
你還要什麼證據?
What more do you want?
掛照片的牆上有血
There's blood on the wall here.
不是除了廚子以外的人  都是在男廁所被殺的嗎?
I thought everyone got shot in the men's room.
那是史丹斯蘭的血
That is Stensland's blood.
史丹斯?  對
Stensland? Yeah.
他頭上被狠狠挨了一記
Blow to the head.
兇手把他拖到男廁時他可能已經昏迷了
Probably unconscious when they dragged him in the john.
他們有沒有打其它的人?
Did they hit anyone else?
沒有  不過他是個警察
No, but he was a cop.
可能想要反抗吧
Probably tried to do something.
吉士三明治  黑咖啡
Grilled cheese, black coffee.
有人跟他坐在一起
Someone was sitting next to him.
有兩個被害人是女的  對吧
對  派蒂·杜魯卡  夜班女服務生
Yeah, Patti DeLuca, the night shift waitress,
還有一位叫做蘇珊·雷佛
and a Susan Lefferts.
蘇珊·雷佛?
Susan Lefferts.
對  怎麼樣?
Yeah, what about her?
不用客氣
You're welcome!
雷佛太太
Mrs. Lefferts
Mrs. Lefferts?
我是洛杉磯警局的懷特警員
I'm Officer White, LAPD.
談談你那天在法院提到的你女兒的那位男友好嗎?
Tell me about the boyfriend you mentioned at the coroner's office.
我跟你們說過  我不喜歡她那個男朋友
I told you I didn't approve of that boyfriend.
他那麼老了跟你不配
He was too old for you.
你還讓他對我那麼兇
And you let him be fresh with me.
有一天我不在家的時候  他們到我家來
They came here one day when I wasn't home.
隔壁的簡森太太她說
Mrs. Jensen next door said
她看見蘇珊的男朋友跟另外一個男人在一起
she saw Susie's boyfriend and another man and
她還說她聽見一陣騷動
she heard a ruckus.
你女兒的男朋友叫什麼名字?
What was his name?
他根本就沒有跟我介紹
We weren't properly introduced.
蘇珊都叫他沐恩魯恩什麼的
Susie gave him a nickname, Muns or Luns.
史丹恩?
Stens?
是不是史丹恩?
Was it Stens?
或許是吧
Maybe.
我不知道
I don't know.
你看看照片
Look.
就是他
That's him.
你說鄰居聽到騷動
You said a neighbor heard a ruckus.
是在外面嗎?還是裏面?
Was it outside? Inside?
在外面
Outside.
簡森太太說他們一直吵吵到房子下面去了
And then Mrs. Jensen said they kept going under the house.
你該走了  警察先生
You have to leave now, officer.
這兒過去是那裏?
-What's through here?
放雜物的房間
-Just a room full of old things.
不要動它
Don't move that!
不要理會那股種臭味了
Don't mind the smell.
大概是有老鼠死在牆後面了
I think a rat died behind the wall.
我的蘇珊是個好女孩
My Susie was a good girl.
她從來沒有惹過任何麻煩的
She was never in any kind of trouble at all!
李蘭·米克斯? 沒聽過
"Leland Meeks." Never heard of you.
他們都叫我巴茲
They call me Buzz.
是不是老鼠?
Was it a rat?
對  好大一隻
Yeah, a great big one.
拿去
Here.
洛杉磯警察局的一點心意
Compliments of the Police Department.
本周兇殺旅館最迷人的胃
Stomach of the week from a motel homicide.
這位失業的演員吃過熱狗  薯條  酒
Unemployed actor had frankfurter, French fries, alcohol and sperm.
還有精液  好豐盛的最後晚餐對不對?
Hell of a last supper, don't you think?
夜貓子那個案子你有沒有覺得不對勁?
Anything bothering you about the Nite Owl case?
有  就是你們一直纏著不放
That you guys won't let it get filed away.
這是什麼意思?
-What do you mean?
巴德·懷特他今天也來問過我
-Bud White grilled me on it today.
巴德·懷特?
Bud White?
他沒有我想的那麼笨
He's not as dumb as I thought.
他跟你說過話後  有沒有說跟你說過要去哪裏
Did he say where he was going after he talked to you?
讓我的女兒安息吧
Let my daughter rest in peace!
雷佛太太  我想問你一些問題
Mrs. Lefferts, I want to ask a few questions.
懷特警官已經去下面看過了
Officer White already checked under the house.
屋子下面?
Under the house?
那裏?  外面後頭
-Where? -Out back.
他只找到老鼠而已
All he found was rodents.
盡快幫我查明死者身份
I need an I.D. on this as soon as possible.
而且你只能向我報告
Talk only to me on this one.
影星首映場前吸毒被捕
文生  我有件事需要你幫忙
I need your help.
我現在很忙你為什麼不找你們兇殺組同仁
I'm busy right now. Why don't you ask your boys in Homicide?
不行  我需要兇殺組以外的人
I can't. I need someone outside of Homicide.
我要你跟蹤巴得懷特直到他今天晚上去值勤為止
Tail Bud White until he goes on duty this evening.
幫幫忙  離我遠一點吧
Do me a real favor and leave me alone.
你相信那三個黑人是夜貓子案的兇手嗎?
You make the Negroes for the Nite Owl killings?
什麼?
What?
這是很簡單的問題
It's a simple question.
你為什麼還要去追查夜貓子的案件呢?
Why in the world do you want to dig deeper into the Nite Owl killings
副組長
Lieutenant?
羅羅·湯馬西
Rollo Tomasi.
你還要給我其它提示還是要我開始猜了?
Is there more or do I have to guess?
羅羅是個扒手
Rollo was a purse snatcher.
先父有一次下了班後捉到他
My father ran into him off-duty.
他朝我父親開了六槍卻逃之夭夭
He shot my father 6 times and got away clean.
沒有人知道他真實的身份
No one knew who he was.
我為了讓這個人真實一點  所以給他取了這個名字
I made the name up to give him personality.
你到底想講什麼?
What's your point?
羅羅·湯馬西是我成為警察的原動力
Rollo Tomasi's the reason I became a cop.
我一心想要捉到
I wanted to catch the guys...
那些自以為可以逍遙法外的人
who thought they could get away with it.
我希望能夠尋得天道公理
It was supposed to be about justice.
可是慢慢的我失去了那份理想
Then somewhere along the way I lost sight of that.
你為什麼當警察?
Why'd you become a cop?
我不記得了
I don't remember.
你到底要什麼?  艾斯利
What do you want, Exley?
我希望能破了這個案子
I want to solve this thing.
夜貓子已經破了
Nite Owl was solved.
沒有
No.
我希望能夠真正的破案
I want to do it right.
即使是你必須付出慘痛代價
Even if it means paying the consequences?
好  大學生  我幫你
All right, college boy, I'll help.
不過有個案子  你們兇殺組根本不在乎
But there's a case your boys in Homicide don't care about.
他們認為只是稀鬆平常的命案
They think it's just another Hollywood "homo"-cide.
可是我不認為
But I don't.
你幫我查我的案子
You help me with mine,
我就幫你查你的案子
I'll help you with yours.
一言為定?
Deal?
一言為定
Deal.
強寧·史當巴那多
Johnny Stompanato.
溫德爾懷特警員  你好嗎? 老兄
Officer Wendell White. How's tricks, paesano?
沒興趣
I amn't your paesano.
我也不再幹線人了
I amn't in the snitch business anymore.
認識一個叫巴茲·米克斯的嗎
You know a guy named Buzz Meeks?
他是皮爾斯·巴卻的手下
Works for Pierce Patchett.
我應該認識他嗎?
Should I?
你是保鏢  米克斯也是保鏢
You're muscle for hire. Meeks is muscle for hire.
你說呢?
You tell me.
哦對  我現在記起來了
Yeah, I remember now.
米克斯是個過氣的老警察了
Meeks is a run-down ex-cop.
有一天你也會跟他一樣的
Same as you're going to be some day.
我只說到這裏了
That's all you'll get.
二十塊錢你自己留著吧
Keep your 20 bucks.
如果我把你的鳥蛋還給你 你能夠告訴我什麼? 傻蛋
What do I get if I give you your balls back, you wop cocksucker?
道上在盛傳
There was a rumor going around
米克斯跟朋友弄到了一大批的海洛因
that Meeks had a line on a large supply of H.
然後呢?
And?
沒有然後了
And nothing!
他拿著貨溜了
He skipped out.
胡說
Bullshit.
米克斯那種人哪有辦法弄到大量海洛因
How would Meeks get his hands on a large supply of heroin?
你說的對
You're right.
可能是胡說八道的吧
It's probably bullshit.
就算他拿到了他也沒辦法賣
Even if he did, he could never unload it.
因為那只會搞的他一身騷
Not without drawing all kinds of attention.
或許就是這樣
Maybe that's why
他才會躺在別人的地下室渾身發臭呢
he's under a house in Elysian Park not smelling too good paesano.
或許懷特真的沒那麼笨哦
Maybe White's not so dumb after all.
麗泰·海華躺在停屍間了
We got Rita Hayworth at the morgue,
而薇洛妮卡跟懷特在一起
and now Veronica Lake with White.
我想你的案子跟我的案子似乎有所關聯
I think your case and my case are connected.
全都扯上了法蘭西王朝
It's Fleur-de-Lis again.
法蘭西王朝?
Fleur-de-Lis?
任君選擇
"Whatever you desire."
應召站
Porno.
整容得像電影明星的高價妓女
High-class whores cut to look like movie stars.
誰知道還有什麼名堂
Who knows what else.
雷諾  那個被殺的小伙子  他也跟法蘭西王朝有關
Reynolds, the kid that got killed, was involved.
皮爾斯·巴卻也是
So is Pierce Patchett.
那個百萬富翁?
The millionaire?
我想我們應該去找他談談
I think we should go talk to him.
不過現在去問問史當巴那多
First I want to brace Stompanato.
要不要簽名?
Want an autograph?
寫信到米高梅(電影公司)吧
Write to MGM.
什麼時候開始  龜公跟妓女也給起簽名照了
Since when do two-bit hoods and hookers give out autographs?
你剛剛說什麼?
What?
洛杉磯警察  坐下
LAPD. Sit down.
你到底以為你是誰?
Who in the hell do you think you are?
出去走一走吧  親愛的  要不然可要請你到局裏去了
Take a walk, honey.Before I send you to downtown…
你犯了天大的錯誤
-You are making a large mistake.
滾遠一點
-Get away from our table.
閉嘴
Shut up.
長的像拉娜·透納的妓女還是個妓女
A hooker cut to look like Lana Turner is still a hooker.
她只是長的像拉娜·透納
-She just looks like Lana Turner.
她就是拉娜·透納
-She is Lana Turner.
- 什麼? - 她就是拉娜·透納
- What? - She is Lana Turner.
我怎麼會知道呢?
How was I supposed to know?
我相信夜貓子那件案子正是你的傑作  艾斯利先生
I believe the Nite Owl's your area of expertise, Mr. Exley.
我在電視上看到你接受獎章
I saw you on television getting your medal.
而你
And you're
是另一個好萊塢明星警察  對不對?
that other Hollywood celebrity policeman, aren't you?
長的向薇洛妮卡的那個女孩是為你工作的
The Veronica Lake look-alike works for you.
她是你旗下女郎之一  對不對?
She's one of your whores.
說的真難聽
A vulgar term.
她為什麼跟巴德·懷特在一起
Why's she seeing Bud White?
男女為什麼在一起呢?
Why do men and women usually see each other?
我們換個話題好了
Let's try this on for size:
法蘭西王朝
Fleur-de-Lis.
任君選擇
"Whatever you desire."
還有一個叫麥特·雷諾的演員
An actor named Matt Reynolds.
沒聽過  一點都不知道?
No? Nothing?
我們需要一些答案
We want some answers.
每個人不都是有所求嗎?
We all want something.
這傢伙非常沉著冷靜
The guy's as cool as they come.
艾斯利警官請回答  完畢
Lieutenant Exley, come in, please. Over.
- 我是艾斯利 - 法醫說要跟你說話
- This is Exley. - The coroner wants to talk to you.
他說他已經查出屍體身份了
He says he has your I.D.
告訴他文生警官會去找他的
Tell him Sergeant Vincennes is coming in to talk to him.
好的  瞭解
Yeah.
我送你回去開你的車
-I'll drop you at your car.
那你要去那裏?
-Where are you going?
琳恩那兒
Lynn Bracken's.
查清楚為什麼巴卻叫她鉤上懷特
To find out why Patchett has her seeing Bud White.
我們到狂歡酒吧見面
See you at the Frolic Room.
太妙了  你找美女
Oh, great. You get the girl.
而我得去找法醫
I get the coroner.
獨家秘聞的噓噓雜誌
Hush-Hush, off the record and on the q.t.
喂  我正要過去找你
I was just coming up to see you.
已經查出身份了嗎?
You get that I.D.?
還好有牙齒的記錄  死者過去是名警察
Thank God for dental records. Stiff used to be a cop.
李蘭·米克斯
Leland Meeks.
巴茲·米克斯?
Buzz Meeks?
你認識他嗎?
-You knew him?
聽說過  我進警界時他還在局裏
-Of him. He was around when I joined the force.
名聲很壞  謝了
Bad rep. Thanks.
說重點就好了
"Just the facts," Jack.
"Just the facts."
還有其它事嗎?警官
Anything else?
米克斯在39到41年在風化組幹過
Leland Meeks worked Vice '39-'41.
我要看看他的抓人記錄
I need to see his arrest records.
佈雷肯小姐  我是艾斯利警官
Miss Bracken I'm Lieutenant Exley.
我知道你是誰
I know who you are.
你的事巴德全跟我說了
Bud told me all about you.
是嗎?
Is that so?
懷特他說了什麼?
And what did White have to say?
他說你很聰明
He said you were smart.
他還說你是個懦夫
He also said you were a coward,
為了功名不計一切
and that you'd screw yourself to get ahead.
你只要記住我很聰明就好了
Let's concentrate on my smarts.
你是皮爾斯·巴卻塑造出來的對不對?
Pierce Patchett made you, didn't he?
他教你如何打扮說話、思考
Taught you how to dress, talk and think.
他的成就真是令人側目
I am very impressed with the results.
可是我希望你回答我一些問題
But I need answers.
否則我就把你跟巴卻抓起來
And if I don't get them, I'll take you and Patchett down.
皮爾斯他會照顧他自己的
Pierce Patchett can take care of himself.
而我根本不怕你
And I'm not afraid of you.
你似乎忘記了一件事情  警官
And you forget one thing, Lieutenant
皮爾斯也教我如何跟男人搞
Pierce also taught me how to fuck.
而且由他指定跟誰搞
And he tells you who to fuck.
你為什麼和巴德·懷特上床
Why does he have you fucking Bud White?
你為什麼認為我不是自願跟巴德交往的呢?
What makes you think I'm not seeing Bud because I want to?
如果我別有居心的話  你心裏會舒坦一點對不對
It would be easier for you if there was an angle, wouldn't it?
你害怕巴德  因為你根本沒有辦法控制他
You're afraid of Bud because you can't figure out how to play him.
他不像你一樣玩弄那一套把戲
He doesn't follow the same rules of politics as you do.
所以使得他變得很危險
It makes him dangerous.
我可以應付得了他
I can handle Bud White.
可以嗎?
Can you?
我見巴德是因為我想
I see Bud because I want to.
我見巴德是因為  他散發出一股善良的本性
I see Bud because he can't hide the good inside of him.
我見巴德是因為  他使我覺得自己是琳恩·佈雷肯
I see Bud because he makes me feel like Lynn Bracken
而不是長的像薇洛妮卡見錢眼開的妓女
and not some Veronica Lake look-alike who fucks for money.
我見巴德是因為他永遠不會隱藏自己
I see Bud because he doesn't know how to disguise who he is.
我會見巴德是因為他跟你截然不同
I see Bud for all the ways he's different from you.
不要低估我
Don't underestimate me.
就像你低估巴德·懷特那樣?
The way you've underestimated Bud White?
搞我跟搞懷特是不同的
Fucking me and fucking Bud aren't the same thing.
不要再提巴德·懷特了
Stop talking about Bud White.
該死
Shit.
傑克·文生
Jack Vincennes.
快午夜了，傑克
It's going on midnight.
一下子就好了  杜德利
I need 2 minutes, Dudley.
很重要的事
It's important.
算你運氣好
Good thing for you...
我老婆跟女兒都到海邊渡假了
My wife and daughters are at the beach in Santa Barbara.
你記得巴茲·米克斯嗎?  杜德利
Do you remember Buzz Meeks, Dudley?
那是警界的恥辱
A disgrace as a police officer.
他歷任的長官都說
Straight D fitness reports from every C.O.
他根本不適合當警察  為什麼?
he ever served under. Why?
十二年前  他跟迪克史丹斯一起進行一次大掃黃
他們就一宗恐嚇案偵訊皮爾斯·巴卻
They questioned Pierce Patchett about a blackmail scam.
當時案情是巴卻叫西德把前景看好的政治家
Patchett had Sid Hudgens photographing prominent...
跟妓女上床的鏡頭給拍了下來
businessmen with hookers.
反正  最後罪名撤銷了
Anyway, charges were dropped.
因為罪證不足
Insufficient evidence.
你是當時那件案子的督察長官
You were the supervising officer on that case.
不知道你還記不記得這件事
Remember anything about it?
這到底是怎麼回事?小伙子
What's this about, boy?
這是跟我還有艾斯利在偵辦的案子有關
It has to do with a murder I've been working with Ed Exley on.
你是緝毒組的不是兇殺組的
You're Narco, Jack, not Homicide.
你什麼時候開始跟艾斯利一起合作了?
Since when do you work with Edmund Exley?
我只是私底下調查一下
It's a private investigation.
我捅出了一些簍子  希望能亡羊補牢
I messed something up. I'm trying to make amends.
別跟人家一樣扮什麼正義俠士
Don't start trying to do the right thing, boyo.
你根本是門外漢
You haven't had the practice.
巴茲·米克斯跟狄克·史丹斯
Buzz Meeks and Dick Stensland.
那艾斯利他有什麼看法呢?
So, what does Exley make of this?
我還沒有告訴他  我剛剛從記錄室那兒過來的
I haven't told him yet. I just came from the records room.
你還有沒有什麼遺言?  小伙子
Have you a valediction, boyo?
羅羅·湯馬西
Rollo Tomasi.
文生是被一把點三二的手槍  射中心臟死的
Sergeant Vincennes was killed by a.32 slug to the heart.
死亡時間大約是深夜一點鐘
Time of death, approximately 1 a.m.
雖然屍體是在艾克公園發現的
Although he was found in Echo Park,
可是法醫認定屍體被疑犯動過
forensics indicates the body was moved.
我希望能夠兩人一組  徹底掃蕩整個地區
I want 2-man teams to scour that entire neighborhood.
務必迅如閃電鐵血無情的  把兇手給抓出來
Our justice must be swift and merciless.
完畢
That is all.
埃德蒙  可以跟你談一下嗎
Might I have a word with you?
我們想追查文生的一位朋友
We're trying to run down a lead on an associate of Vincennes.
可是一查下去卻是個死胡同
The records check has led to a dead end.
那個人叫什麼名字?
What's the name?
羅羅·湯馬西
Rollo Tomasi?
你有沒有聽文生提起過他?
You ever heard Vincennes mention him?
沒有  沒有聽過
No. No, I haven't.
這可能沒有什麼
It's probably nothing. Still
不過你還是注意一下好嗎?
keep your eyes open, boyo.
我知道是不太可能  不過假設
I know it's unlikely, but suppose,
只是假設
just for a moment
有人拿到了一大批海洛因
somebody had a lot of heroin,
你看他會拿去賣給誰?
who would they go to move it?
懷特  到我辦公室來
White, in my office.
好的
Captain.
快一點  隨便說一個嘛
Look, just give me a name.
米奇·柯漢
Mickey Cohen.
組長  我需要你到勝利旅館去一趟
Captain? I could use your fearsome habits at the Victory Motel.
什麼時候?
When?
現在  溫德爾
Now.
把門關起來
Close the door, lad.
我最近實在搞不懂你
You're a bit of a puzzlement to me these days.
怎麼好像變的軟趴趴
You don't seem your old cruel self.
我對你的未來可是有著深遠的打算的
And I had such grand plans for your future.
什麼打算?
What plans?
你當然會有自己的一些私事  我也一樣
You have your extracurricular activities and I have mine.
不過咱們改天得找個時間  好好談談我們的未來
We must have a clarification session one of these days.
不過眼前呢
However right now
我們要偵訊一個  知道是誰殺死傑克·文生的人
we'll brace a man who may know who killed Jack Vincennes.
所以現在的問題是
So the question is
我可以信任你嗎?可不可以?
can I count on you, lad?
可以  長官
-Yes or no? -Yes, sir.
我要知道你昨晚到底跟傑克談了些什麼
I want to know everything you and Jack Vincennes talked about last night.
就從屍體的身份開始
Start with the I.D. on the corpse.
那個死者以前是一位警察
An ex-cop.
李蘭巴茲·米克斯
Leland "Buzz" Meeks.
以前是警察?
An ex-cop?
傑克怎麼說?他認識他嗎?
Did Jack know him?
只是聽說過而已
Only by reputation.
溫德爾  這位是西·德哈金斯
This is Sid Hudgens.
我願意合作
I'm willing to cooperate.
沒有必要把我綁起來
No need to tie me down.
這是為了你的安全著想
It's for your own safety.
你對傑克·文生警官知道些什麼呢?
What can you tell us about Jack Vincennes?
好萊塢傑克  那個大騷包
Hollywood Jack? The Big V?
他已經踏上奈何橋了
I can tell you he's on the night train to the Big Adios.
我跟他的死沒有任何關係
I had nothing to do with him getting killed,
你是不是要問這個?
if that's what you mean.
可是你們不是合夥人嗎?
-But you were business associates.
這跟他的死有什麼關係
-What's that got to do with anything?
好  我們是一起合作
Okay, so we worked together.
不過是互相交換消息嘛
It was an information exchange.
我幫他找出一些要犯
I got him first-class collars,
而他提供我一些好的題材
he got me good stories.
我們只是朋友而已
We were friends.
好了  暫時先別談傑克了
We'll drop that for the moment.
可以談談皮爾斯·巴卻嗎?
Care to comment on Pierce Patchett?
巴卻? 你想他跟文生的死有關嗎?
You think he had something to do with Vincennes getting iced?
我希望我問話的時候  對方能夠完全跟我合作
Wendell, I'd like full and docile cooperation on every topic.
好啦好啦
Okay, okay, okay. All right.
每個人都知道巴卻他腰纏萬貫
Everyone knows Patchett's worth a boatload of greenbacks.
不過那個人也有一些嗜好的
But the man has hobbies too.
他私底下會出資拍一些黃色電影
He bankrolls B movies under the table.
你再聽聽這個
And try this one on.
另外聽說他還會吸毒
He's rumored to be a heroin snuffer.
總之一句話  他是一個深入簡出的怪富豪
All in all, a powerful behind-the-scenes strange-o.
還有呢?  還有什麼?
And? And what?
人跟人相處是互相的
Reciprocity, Mr. Hudgens, is the key to every relationship.
他還開了應召站
He runs call girls.
整容整得像電影明星的妓女
Primo tail fixed up to look like movie stars.
還有呢?
And?
還有他也搞勒索那一套
Blackmail shit.
我車上  行李箱地毯下面
In my car, in the trunk, under the rug.
巴卻給了我一些警察
Patchett got me to photograph...
跟一個叫琳恩的女人上床的照片
this cop screwing this gorgeous slut named Lynn.
那女的長得像薇洛妮卡
She looks like Veronica Lake.
放開他
Leave him!
我叫你放開他
I said leave him be!
快點把他拉走
Get him away from me!
退後
Back off! Back off!
就算全愛爾蘭的威士忌都給我
I wouldn't trade places with Exley right now
我都不願意跟艾斯利交換位置
for all the whiskey in Ireland.
杜德利
Dudley
杜德利  我還以為你會讓那個笨蛋把我給宰了呢
Dudley, I thought you were going to let the dumb bastard kill me!
還有你
And you.
下次別真的揍下去行嗎?
Learn to pull your punches a little better.
現在可以把我給放了吧
You can uncaught me now, fellas.
喂  各位
Fellas
杜德利  我們說好的
we had a deal.
你  我跟巴卻  我們是一夥的
You, me, Patchett, we're a team.
噓噓
Hush-hush.
有沒有?  沒有
-Anything? -Nothing.
難道米克斯在掃毒組沒抓過人
Meeks never made an arrest the entire time he worked Vice?
一定是有人把檔案拿走了
Someone must've pulled the files.
那日常勤務報告呢?
What about the daily report books?
如果還在一定是放在地下室
They'd be buried in the basement.
去找出來
Find them.
你跟艾斯利談過話?
Did you talk to Exley?
先進來避雨
Come in out of the rain.
你跟艾斯利是怎麼回事?
I want to know what happened with Exley.
你進來
Just come in.
你到底要不要告訴我  你跟艾斯利是怎麼回事?
Are you going to tell me what happened with Exley?
我們說過話
We talked.
把他的事告訴我
Tell me about him.
- 待會兒  - 不  現在
- Later. - No!Now!
你跟他搞過
You fucked him.
我以為我是在幫你
I thought I was helping you.
米克斯與史丹斯蘭謹呈
杜德利·史密斯長官鈞啟
茲此呈上本報告
你來的正好
I'm glad you're here.
快過來看看這個
I need you to see this.
等一下
Wait.
杜德利殺了傑克
Dudley killed Jack.
他希望你把我殺了
He wants you to kill me.
是他把照片給你看的對不對
He showed you the photo, didn't he?
對不對?
Didn't he?
你想一想  該死  想一想
Think!! Goddamn you, think!!
統統滾開
Get out!
杜德利
Dudley
我查過日常勤務報告
I checked the daily report books.
杜德利  巴茲·米克斯以及史丹斯蘭  早就同流合污了
Dudley, Buzz Meeks and Stensland go way back.
我早知道史丹斯蘭在騙我
I knew Stensland lied to me.
雷佛的母親認出了史丹斯蘭  就是雷佛的男友
Lefferts' mother I.D.'d Stensland as Lefferts' boyfriend.
我碰見琳恩那晚史丹斯蘭
Stensland pretended he didn't know Meeks...
他還裝作不認識米克斯
or her the night that I met Lynn.
史丹斯蘭跟米克斯
Stensland and Meeks
他們到底在搞什麼把戲?
what the hell were they up to?
我不知道
I don't know.
不過我想史丹斯蘭  為了海洛因殺了米克斯
But I think Stens killed Meeks over heroin.
什麼海洛因?
What heroin?
強寧·史當巴那多告訴我米克斯手上有海洛因要賣
Johnny Stompanato told me that Meeks had heroin for sale.
結果米克斯死了
Meeks ends up dead.
而史丹斯蘭也死在夜貓子
Stensland dies at the Nite Owl.
兇手不是那些黑人
It wasn't the Negroes.
被強暴的被害人說謊
The rape victim lied in her statement.
最先趕到福特跑車那兒的是  布魯尼跟卡爾萊
The first guys to the Mercury coupe were Breuning and Carlisle.
是杜德利的人
Dudley's guys.
散彈鎗是他們栽的贓
They planted the shotguns.
如果我跟傑克沒有出現
They'd have killed the Negroes too
它們當場就會把那些黑人殺了
if Jack and I hadn't shown up.
杜德利會栽他們贓  是因為他們是黑人又有前科
Dudley framed them because they were Negroes and had records.
他知道如果他們因為拒捕被殺
He knew there'd be no questions asked
就不會有任何人起疑
if they were killed resisting arrest.
而此事又跟傑克所調查的事有關
Somehow this is all connected to Jack's angle.
西·德哈金斯
Sid Hudgens
勒索羅的照片
the pictures to blackmail Ellis Loew.
被殺的那個年輕人
A kid got murdered.
如果想弄清此事我們就得合作
To figure this out, we need to work together.
你為什麼這麼做?
Why are you doing this?
夜貓子使你功名成就
The Nite Owl made you.
你希望這一切成為泡影?
You want to tear all that down?
而且煙消雲散
With a wrecking ball.
要不要幫我大幹一場?
Want to help me swing it?
去找艾力斯羅吧
Let's go see Ellis Loew.
看看檢察官知道些什麼
Find out what the District Attorney knows.
喂  你們不能進去
You can't go in there.
要不要我報警  羅先生?
-Want me to call the police, Mr. Loew?
你就找杜德利·史密斯組長
-Ask for Capt. Dudley Smith.
告訴他我們在討論
Tell him we're discussing...
演員陳屍日落大道旅館的事
an unemployed actor's death at a Sunset Strip motel.
他們就是警察
These are the police.
你們有什麼事?
What do you want?
我要檢察處派人二十四小時
I want D.A. bureau men to
監視杜德利·史密斯跟皮爾斯
tail Dudley Smith and Patchett 24 hours a day.
我要你讓法官准許監聽他們的電話
I want you to get a judge to authorize wiretaps on their home phones.
還有查他們銀行記錄的許可令
I want authorization to check their bank records.
憑什麼證據?
On what evidence?
就憑我的直覺
Call it a hunch.
絕對不行
Absolutely not.
杜德利是警局功勳卓著的人
Dudley Smith is a highly decorated member of the department.
我不會毀了他跟皮爾斯的名譽
I won't smear his and Patchett's name without--
除非  除非怎樣?
Without what?
他們先毀了你的名譽?
Them smearing yours first?
你有什麼把柄在他們手上?
What do they have?
你跟雷諾一絲不掛的照片?
Pictures of you and Matt Reynolds with your pants down?
你有證據嗎?
You have any proof?
證人已經被宰了
The proof had his throat slit.
到目前為止  你並未否認
So far, you're not denying it.
我不屑於做任何回答
I won't dignify this with answers.
如果二位不介意的話
Now if you gentlemen will excuse me
我還得去向記者說明傑克·文生遇害的事
I have a press conference for Jack Vincennes that I have to prepare for.
除非你們是要來替我擦屁股的
Unless you came to wipe my ass,
否則我們之間好像沒什麼事了
I believe we're through.
好了  少來白臉黑臉那一套了
Don't pull that good cop-bad cop crap.
我還是開山始祖呢
I practically invented it.
死了個同性戀男演員又怎樣
So what if some homo actor is dead.
男男女女  這種人滿街都是
Boys, girls, ten of them get off the bus to L.A. everyday.
叫他放開我  艾斯利
Pull him off me!!
我不知道怎麼跟他說
I don't know how.
我知道你自以為是頭號大人物
I know you think you're the A-number-one hotshot,
不過老實說
but here's the juice.
如果我把你殺了
If I kill you,
明天馬上會有十個律師來接你的位子
只是他們可不是滿街都是
They just won't come on a bus.
好啦
Okay!
杜德利跟巴卻他們
Dudley and Patchett, they.
哦  我的天
Oh, my God!
因為我不肯同流合污
I wouldn't play ball
所以他們設計陷害我  我只好屈服
so they set me up! I gave in!
那個年輕人正好聽見了經過
But the kid heard everything
所以他們把他給殺了
so they killed him.
為什麼?杜德利跟皮爾斯有什麼陰謀?
Why? -What are Dudley and Patchett up to?
他們要接手柯漢的盤口
-Taking over Mickey Cohen's rackets.
因為有了那些照片  我無法起訴他們
Because of those pictures I couldn't prosecute them!
哦  天啊
Oh, Jesus!
拉我起來
Help me up!
你以前是這麼玩黑臉白臉的嗎
Is that how you ran the good cop-bad cop?
巴卻?
Patchett?
看來他的保鏢喜新厭舊了
Looks like his bodyguard had a conflict of interest.
自殺遺書上頭說
Suicide note.
傑克發現了他開應召站  所以他殺了傑克
Says he killed Jack because Jack had figured out his pornography scam.
他不是自殺的
Slicing himself open wasn't his idea.
他有兩根手指頭裂開了
兇手硬把他拖過來的
They held him there.
或是用藥把他迷昏了
Or drugged him.
杜德利想亡羊補牢
Dudley's tying up his loose ends.
巴卻死了
Patchett's dead.
他又派你來殺我
He sent you after me.
琳恩?
Lynn.
通知西好萊塢警長
West Hollywood Sheriff.
他們那兒比我們近
-They're closer than we are.
我去開車
-I'll get the car.
鑰匙
Keys!
我們把她送到局裏保護了
We took her to the station for safekeeping.
把她當瓊史密斯
Hold her as Joan Smith.
除非我允許否則不許任何人見她
And no one sees her unless I okay it.
有人打過她
Someone worked her over.
她不肯說是誰
She wouldn't say who.
再見  艾斯利  再見
See you, Exley.
我們應該去跟琳恩談談
We should talk to Lynn.
你去
You do it.
那你呢?
What will you do?
我去找西·德哈金斯
I'm going to talk to Sid Hudgens.
好好誇獎一下他在勝利旅館的演技
Compliment him on his performance at the Victory Motel.
記住  巴德  我們需要證據
Remember, Bud, we need evidence.
我會拿到證據的
I'll get the evidence.
你還好吧?
Are you okay?
You okay?
巴德很後悔打了你
Bud hates himself for what he did.
我知道他心裏的感受
I know how he feels.
我必須知道你有什麼  不利於杜德斯史密斯的證據
I need to know what you can give me on Dudley Smith.
他是跟巴卻同流合污的警官
He's a police captain in business with Patchett.
我沒聽過這個人
I've never heard of him.
你有沒有地方可以去?
Do you have a place to stay?
我不會有事的
I'll be okay.
沒有證件的人不可以進去
Nobody goes in without official I.D.!
他沒關係  讓他進來
He's okay. Let him through.
發生了什麼事?
What happened?
有人把他活活打死然後偷走了一大堆檔案
Someone beat him to death, and stole a bunch of files.
一定是他去揭人家的瘡疤
Must have dug up garbage on the wrong guy.
所以範圍縮小到一千人左右
We got it narrowed down to 1000 suspects.
懷特警員
Sergeant White
勤務中心接到你的電話
dispatch got a call for you.
艾斯利警官要你到勝利旅館去找他
Lieutenant Exley wants you to meet him at the Victory Motel.
你要我到這兒找你?
You wanted to meet here?
- 是你說的 我以為哈金斯… - 他已經死了
- You called it. I thought Hudgens was… - Hudgens is dead.
我們快走
Let's get out of here.
來不及了
It's too late.
你懷疑是圈套還來?
You figured it was a set-up but came anyway?
這兒發生了太多壞事了
A lot of bad stuff happened here.
所有恩怨正好在這兒做個了結
It's as good a place as any for it to end.
彈夾
Clip.
我只是想追上先父而已
All I ever wanted was to measure up to my father.
你的機會來了
Now's your chance.
他是因公殉職的對不對?
He died in the line of duty, didn't he?
巴德
Bud.
該死
Goddamn it!
你沒事吧?
You okay?
沒事
Yeah.
起來
Come on. Easy.
走
Move!
羅羅·湯馬西
Rollo Tomasi.
他是誰?
Who is he?
就是你
You are.
你就是那個逍遙法外的人
You're the guy who gets away with it.
傑克他知道了
Jack knew it.
我也知道了
And so do l.
你是打算殺了我
Are you going to shoot me
還是要逮捕我?
or arrest me?
好孩子
Good lad.
永遠是那麼聰明
Always the politician.
由我來出面說明
Let me do the talking.
等我說明完了  此後
After I'm done,
你馬上可以升為刑事組長
they'll make you Chief of Detectives.
把警徽舉高一點
Hold up your badge
他們才會知道你是警察
so they'll know you're a policeman.
你以為這麼輕易就可以脫罪
You think you can talk your way out of this, Lieutenant?
不  不過我可以說出真相
No but I can tell the truth.
在調查與夜貓子案相關的事件時
During our investigation of events surrounding the Nite Owl case
傑克·文生  巴德·懷特跟我本人發現了下列事惰
Jack Vincennes, Bud White and I learned the following:
你的金童正在自毀前程
Your golden boy's throwing his whole life away.
夜貓子案之三名嫌犯
The 3 Nite Owl suspects
確實犯了強姦綁架罪
while guilty of kidnapping and rape
卻並未在夜貓子犯下殺人案
were innocent of the multiple homicides at the Nite Owl.
夜貓子的真正兇手極有可能是
The gunmen were most likely
洛杉磯警察麥可布魯因以及威廉卡爾萊
Los Angeles police officers Michael Breuning and William Carlisle
至於第三個人
and a third man
可能是  也可能不是史密斯組長
who may or may not have been Captain Dudley Smith.
他們殺人之目的乃是
The objective:
為了幹掉另一名警員
The elimination of another police officer
狄克·史丹斯
Richard Stensland
該員跟一名洛杉磯離職警員李蘭巴茲·米克斯
who, along with former LAPD officer Leland "Buzz" Meeks
曾經為史密斯組長犯下數起殺人案
also committed multiple homicides on behalf of Captain Smith
後來又為了二十五磅海洛因  而出賣了史密斯組長
and then betrayed him over 25 pounds of heroin
而夜貓子案幕後真正的動機
the retrieval of which
正是為了取回那些海洛因
was the ultimate motivation behind the Nite Owl killings.
自米奇·柯漢入獄開始
Beginning with the incarceration of Mickey Cohen
史密斯組長便圖謀接管洛杉磯的黑社會
Capt. Smith has been assuming control of organized crime in Los Angeles.
其手段包括了暗殺柯漢的手下
This includes the assassinations of Mickey Cohen lieutenants
循序恐嚇政府官員
the systematic blackmail of city officials
以及殺害蘇珊雷佛
and the murders of Susan Lefferts,
皮爾斯·巴卻  西·德哈金斯
Pierce Patchett, Sid Hudgens
以及傑克·文生警官
and Sergeant Jack Vincennes.
史密斯組長在勝利汽車旅館
Captain Smith admitted as much to me
被我射殺之前向我坦承了一切
before I shot him at the Victory Motel.
說完了
That's it.
好了  媒體這下可樂翻天了
Well the press will have a field day.
這將使本局未來幾年抬不起頭
Christ! It'll stain the Department for years.
未來幾十年
Decades.
如果我們能讓孩子上道一點
If we can get the kid to play ball
那還有誰會說出去呢
who's to say what happened?
或許史密斯是像英雄般殉職的
Maybe Dudley Smith died a hero.
好主意  如果媒體肯跟我們合作
-Good idea. -lf we get the press to play.
要不要告訴我你在笑什麼
Want to tell me what you're smiling about?
英雄
A hero.
他怎麼知道我們在說什麼
How'd he know what we said?
他不可能聽見的
He couldn't have heard us.
在這種情況下
In this situation
一個英雄是不夠的
you'll need more than one.
"警局組長英雄般殉職 "
本人深感榮幸能再一次
It is my pleasure to present this award to
頒發勇士勳章給埃德蒙艾斯利警官
Detective Lieutenant Edmund Exley two-time Medal of Valor recipient.
本局明年將遷至新大樓
Next year the LAPD will move into its new facility.
有了艾斯利這樣的楷模
With leaders like Edmund Exley
本局同仁貪污舞弊的惡劣形象  將一掃而空
the image of fat cops stealing apples will be left behind
洛杉磯也終於有了應有的警力
and Los Angeles will finally have the police force it deserves.
你就是受不了誘惑
You just couldn't resist.
他們要利用我嘛  我又何妨也利用利用他們
They're using me. So for a while, I'm using them.
出來一下
Come on.
謝謝你推了我一把
Thanks for the push.
恭喜你了  警官
Congratulations, Lieutenant Exley.
有人贏得了全世界
Some men get the world
有人則贏得了從良妓女  以及亞歷桑那之旅
others get ex-hookers and a trip to Arizona.